From,IN,O
this,DT,O
climate,NN,O
William,NNP,I-PER
Godwin,NNP,I-PER
developed,VBD,O
what,WP,O
many,NN,O
consider,VBP,O
the,DT,O
first,JJ,O
expression,NN,O
of,IN,O
modern,JJ,O
anarchist,NN,O
thought,NN,O
.,.,O
Godwin,NNP,I-PER
was,VBD,O
",",",",O
according,VBG,O
to,TO,O
Peter,NNP,I-PER
Kropotkin,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
"""",LQU,O
the,DT,O
first,JJ,O
to,TO,O
formulate,VB,O
the,DT,O
political,JJ,O
and,CC,O
economical,JJ,O
conceptions,NNS,O
of,IN,O
anarchism,NN,O
",",",",O
even,RB,O
though,IN,O
he,PRP,O
did,VBD,O
not,RB,O
give,VB,O
that,DT,O
name,NN,O
to,TO,O
the,DT,O
ideas,NNS,O
developed,VBN,O
in,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
work,NN,O
"""",RQU,O
",",",",O
while,IN,O
Godwin,NNP,I-PER
attached,VBD,O
his,PRP$,O
anarchist,NN,O
ideas,NNS,O
to,TO,O
an,DT,O
early,JJ,O
Edmund,NNP,I-PER
Burke,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
Its,PRP$,O
classical,JJ,O
period,NN,O
",",",",O
which,WDT,O
scholars,NNS,O
demarcate,VBP,O
as,IN,O
from,IN,O
1860,CD,O
to,TO,O
1939,CD,O
",",",",O
is,VBZ,O
associated,VBN,O
with,IN,O
the,DT,O
working-class,JJ,O
movements,NNS,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
nineteenth,JJ,O
century,NN,O
and,CC,O
the,DT,O
Spanish,NNP,I-MISC
Civil,NNP,I-MISC
War-era,NNP,I-MISC
struggles,VBZ,O
against,IN,O
fascism,NN,O
.,.,O
Karl,NNP,I-PER
Marx,NNP,I-PER
became,VBD,O
a,DT,O
leading,JJ,O
figure,NN,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,I-MISC
International,NNP,I-MISC
and,CC,O
a,DT,O
member,NN,O
of,IN,O
its,PRP$,O
General,NNP,I-ORG
Council,NNP,I-ORG
.,.,O
Proudhon,NNP,I-PER
's,POS,O
followers,NNS,O
",",",",O
the,DT,O
mutualists,NNS,O
",",",",O
opposed,VBD,O
Marx,NNP,I-PER
's,POS,O
state,NN,O
socialism,NN,O
",",",",O
advocating,VBG,O
political,JJ,O
abstentionism,NN,O
and,CC,O
small,JJ,O
property,NN,O
holdings,NNS,O
.,.,O
They,PRP,O
allied,VBD,O
themselves,PRP,O
with,IN,O
the,DT,O
federalist,JJ,O
socialist,JJ,O
sections,NNS,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,I-MISC
International,NNP,I-MISC
",",",",O
who,WP,O
advocated,VBD,O
the,DT,O
revolutionary,JJ,O
overthrow,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
and,CC,O
the,DT,O
collectivization,NN,O
of,IN,O
property,NN,O
.,.,O
Subsequently,RB,O
",",",",O
the,DT,I-MISC
International,NNP,I-MISC
became,VBD,O
polarised,VBN,O
into,IN,O
two,CD,O
camps,NNS,O
",",",",O
with,IN,O
Marx,NNP,I-PER
and,CC,O
Bakunin,NNP,I-PER
as,IN,O
their,PRP$,O
respective,JJ,O
figureheads,NNS,O
.,.,O
In,IN,O
response,NN,O
",",",",O
unions,NNS,O
across,IN,O
America,NNP,I-LOC
prepared,VBD,O
a,DT,O
general,JJ,O
strike,NN,O
in,IN,O
support,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
event,NN,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
incident,NN,O
became,VBD,O
known,VBN,O
as,IN,O
the,DT,O
Haymarket,NNP,I-PER
affair,NN,I-PER
",",",",O
and,CC,O
was,VBD,O
a,DT,O
setback,NN,O
for,IN,O
the,DT,O
labour,NN,O
movement,NN,O
and,CC,O
the,DT,O
struggle,NN,O
for,IN,O
the,DT,O
eight,CD,O
hour,NN,O
day,NN,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
event,NN,O
also,RB,O
had,VBD,O
the,DT,O
secondary,JJ,O
purpose,NN,O
of,IN,O
memorializing,VBG,O
workers,NNS,O
killed,VBN,O
as,IN,O
a,DT,O
result,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
Haymarket,NNP,I-PER
affair,NN,I-PER
.,.,O
The,DT,O
most,RBS,O
successful,JJ,O
was,VBD,O
the,DT,O
Confederación,NNP,I-ORG
Nacional,NNP,I-ORG
del,NNP,I-ORG
Trabajo,NNP,I-ORG
(,LRB,O
National,NNP,I-ORG
Confederation,NNP,I-ORG
of,IN,I-ORG
Labour,NNP,I-ORG
:,IN,O
CNT,NNP,I-ORG
),RRB,O
",",",",O
founded,VBN,O
in,IN,O
1910,CD,O
.,.,O
CGT,NNP,I-ORG
membership,NN,O
was,VBD,O
estimated,VBN,O
to,TO,O
be,VB,O
around,IN,O
"100,000",CD,O
for,IN,O
the,DT,O
year,NN,O
2003,CD,O
.,.,O
Other,JJ,O
active,JJ,O
syndicalist,NN,O
movements,NNS,O
include,VBP,O
the,DT,O
US,NNP,I-LOC
Workers,NNPS,I-ORG
Solidarity,NNP,I-ORG
Alliance,NNP,I-ORG
and,CC,O
the,DT,O
UK,NNP,I-LOC
Solidarity,NNP,I-ORG
Federation,NNP,I-ORG
.,.,O
Some,DT,O
anarchists,NNS,O
",",",",O
such,JJ,O
as,IN,O
Johann,NNP,I-PER
Most,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
advocated,VBD,O
publicizing,VBG,O
violent,JJ,O
acts,NNS,O
of,IN,O
retaliation,NN,O
against,IN,O
counter-revolutionaries,NNS,O
because,IN,O
"""",LQU,O
we,PRP,O
preach,VBP,O
not,RB,O
only,RB,O
action,NN,O
in,IN,O
and,CC,O
for,IN,O
itself,PRP,O
",",",",O
but,CC,O
also,RB,O
action,NN,O
as,IN,O
propaganda,NN,O
.,.,O
"""",RQU,O
The,DT,O
anarcho-syndicalist,NN,O
",",",",O
Fernand,NNP,I-PER
Pelloutier,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
argued,VBD,O
in,IN,O
1895,CD,O
for,IN,O
renewed,VBN,O
anarchist,NN,O
involvement,NN,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
labor,NN,O
movement,NN,O
on,IN,O
the,DT,O
basis,NN,O
that,IN,O
anarchism,NN,O
could,MD,O
do,VB,O
very,RB,O
well,RB,O
without,IN,O
"""",LQU,O
the,DT,O
individual,JJ,O
dynamiter,NN,O
.,.,O
This,DT,O
was,VBD,O
in,IN,O
spite,NN,O
of,IN,O
Goldman,NNP,I-PER
's,POS,O
disavowal,NN,O
of,IN,O
any,DT,O
association,NN,O
with,IN,O
him,PRP,O
",",",",O
his,PRP$,O
registered,JJ,O
membership,NN,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
Republican,NNP,I-ORG
Party,NNP,I-ORG
",",",",O
and,CC,O
never,RB,O
having,VBG,O
belonged,VBN,O
to,TO,O
an,DT,O
anarchist,NN,O
organization,NN,O
.,.,O
Propaganda,NNP,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
deed,NN,O
was,VBD,O
abandoned,VBN,O
by,IN,O
the,DT,O
vast,JJ,O
majority,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
anarchist,NN,O
movement,NN,O
after,IN,O
World,NNP,I-MISC
War,NNP,I-MISC
I,NNP,I-MISC
(,LRB,O
1914,CD,O
--,:,O
18,CD,O
),RRB,O
and,CC,O
the,DT,O
1917,CD,I-MISC
October,NNP,I-MISC
Revolution,NN,I-MISC
.,.,O
Anarchists,NNS,O
participated,VBD,O
alongside,IN,O
the,DT,O
Bolsheviks,NNS,I-ORG
in,IN,O
both,DT,O
February,NNP,O
and,CC,O
October,NNP,I-MISC
revolutions,NNS,I-MISC
",",",",O
and,CC,O
were,VBD,O
initially,RB,O
enthusiastic,JJ,O
about,IN,O
the,DT,O
Bolshevik,NNP,I-ORG
coup,NN,O
.,.,O
However,RB,O
",",",",O
the,DT,O
Bolsheviks,NNP,I-ORG
soon,RB,O
turned,VBD,O
against,IN,O
the,DT,O
anarchists,NNS,O
and,CC,O
other,JJ,O
left-wing,JJ,O
opposition,NN,O
",",",",O
a,DT,O
conflict,NN,O
that,WDT,O
culminated,VBD,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
1921,CD,O
Kronstadt,NNP,I-MISC
rebellion,NN,I-MISC
which,WDT,O
the,DT,O
new,JJ,O
government,NN,O
repressed,VBD,O
.,.,O
Both,DT,O
wrote,VBD,O
accounts,NNS,O
of,IN,O
their,PRP$,O
experiences,NNS,O
in,IN,O
Russia,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
criticizing,VBG,O
the,DT,O
amount,NN,O
of,IN,O
control,NN,O
the,DT,O
Bolsheviks,NNPS,I-ORG
exercised,VBD,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
victory,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
Bolsheviks,NNS,I-ORG
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
October,NNP,I-MISC
Revolution,NN,I-MISC
and,CC,O
the,DT,O
resulting,VBG,O
Russian,NNP,I-MISC
Civil,NNP,I-MISC
War,NNP,I-MISC
did,VBD,O
serious,JJ,O
damage,NN,O
to,TO,O
anarchist,NN,O
movements,NNS,O
internationally,RB,O
.,.,O
Italian,JJ,I-ORG
anarchists,NNS,I-ORG
played,VBD,O
a,DT,O
key,JJ,O
role,NN,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
anti-fascist,JJ,O
organisation,NN,O
Arditi,NNP,I-MISC
del,NNP,I-MISC
Popolo,NNP,I-MISC
",",",",O
which,WDT,O
was,VBD,O
strongest,JJS,O
in,IN,O
areas,NNS,O
with,IN,O
anarchist,JJ,O
traditions,NNS,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
achieved,VBD,O
some,DT,O
success,NN,O
in,IN,O
their,PRP$,O
activism,NN,O
",",",",O
such,JJ,O
as,IN,O
repelling,VBG,O
Blackshirts,NNS,I-ORG
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
anarchist,NN,O
stronghold,NN,O
of,IN,O
Parma,NNP,I-LOC
in,IN,O
August,NNP,O
1922,CD,O
.,.,O
But,CC,O
in,IN,O
1936,CD,O
",",",",O
the,DT,O
CNT,NNP,I-ORG
changed,VBD,O
its,PRP$,O
policy,NN,O
and,CC,O
anarchist,NN,O
votes,NNS,O
helped,VBD,O
bring,VB,O
the,DT,O
popular,JJ,O
front,NN,O
back,RB,O
to,TO,O
power,NN,O
.,.,O
Months,NNS,O
later,RB,O
",",",",O
the,DT,O
former,JJ,O
ruling,NN,O
class,NN,O
responded,VBD,O
with,IN,O
an,DT,O
attempted,VBN,O
coup,NN,O
causing,VBG,O
the,DT,O
Spanish,JJ,I-MISC
Civil,NNP,I-MISC
War,NNP,I-MISC
(,LRB,O
1936,CD,O
--,:,O
1939,CD,O
),RRB,O
.,.,O
In,IN,O
the,DT,O
U.K.,NNP,I-LOC
this,DT,O
was,VBD,O
associated,VBN,O
with,IN,O
the,DT,O
punk,NN,O
rock,NN,O
movement,NN,O
",",",",O
as,IN,O
exemplified,VBN,O
by,IN,O
bands,NNS,O
such,JJ,O
as,IN,O
Crass,NNP,I-ORG
and,CC,O
the,DT,O
Sex,NN,I-ORG
Pistols,NNS,I-ORG
.,.,O
Anarchist,NNP,O
anthropologist,NN,O
David,NNP,I-PER
Graeber,NNP,I-PER
and,CC,O
anarchist,JJ,O
historian,NN,O
Andrej,NNP,I-PER
Grubacic,NNP,I-PER
have,VBP,O
posited,VBN,O
a,DT,O
rupture,NN,O
between,IN,O
generations,NNS,O
of,IN,O
anarchism,NN,O
",",",",O
with,IN,O
those,DT,O
"""",LQU,O
who,WP,O
often,RB,O
still,RB,O
have,VBP,O
not,RB,O
shaken,VBN,O
the,DT,O
sectarian,JJ,O
habits,NNS,O
"""",RQU,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
nineteenth,JJ,O
century,NN,O
contrasted,VBD,O
with,IN,O
the,DT,O
younger,JJR,O
activists,NNS,O
who,WP,O
are,VBP,O
"""",LQU,O
much,RB,O
more,RBR,O
informed,JJ,O
",",",",O
among,IN,O
other,JJ,O
elements,NNS,O
",",",",O
by,IN,O
indigenous,JJ,O
",",",",O
feminist,JJ,O
",",",",O
ecological,JJ,O
and,CC,O
cultural-critical,JJ,O
ideas,NNS,O
"""",RQU,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
who,WP,O
by,IN,O
the,DT,O
turn,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
21st,JJ,O
century,NN,O
formed,VBN,O
"""",LQU,O
by,IN,O
far,RB,O
the,DT,O
majority,NN,O
"""",RQU,O
of,IN,O
anarchists,NNS,O
.,.,O
Anarchists,NNS,O
became,VBD,O
known,VBN,O
for,IN,O
their,PRP$,O
involvement,NN,O
in,IN,O
protests,NNS,O
against,IN,O
the,DT,O
meetings,NNS,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
World,NNP,I-ORG
Trade,NNP,I-ORG
Organization,NNP,I-ORG
(,LRB,O
WTO,NNP,I-ORG
),RRB,O
",",",",O
Group,NNP,I-ORG
of,IN,I-ORG
Eight,CD,I-ORG
",",",",O
and,CC,O
the,DT,O
World,NNP,I-ORG
Economic,NNP,I-ORG
Forum,NNP,I-ORG
.,.,O
A,DT,O
landmark,JJ,O
struggle,NN,O
of,IN,O
this,DT,O
period,NN,O
was,VBD,O
the,DT,O
confrontations,NNS,O
at,IN,O
WTO,NNP,I-ORG
conference,NN,I-ORG
in,IN,I-ORG
Seattle,NNP,I-ORG
in,IN,I-ORG
1999,CD,I-ORG
.,.,O
One,CD,O
reaction,NN,O
against,IN,O
sectarianism,NN,O
within,IN,O
the,DT,O
anarchist,NN,O
milieu,NN,O
was,VBD,O
"""",LQU,O
anarchism,NN,O
without,IN,O
adjectives,NNS,O
"""",RQU,O
",",",",O
a,DT,O
call,NN,O
for,IN,O
toleration,NN,O
first,RB,O
adopted,VBN,O
by,IN,O
Fernando,NNP,I-PER
Tarrida,NNP,I-PER
del,NNP,I-PER
Mármol,NNP,I-PER
in,IN,O
1889,CD,O
in,IN,O
response,NN,O
to,TO,O
the,DT,O
"""",LQU,O
bitter,JJ,O
debates,NNS,O
"""",RQU,O
of,IN,O
anarchist,NN,O
theory,NN,O
at,IN,O
the,DT,O
time,NN,O
.,.,O
Proudhon,NNP,I-PER
proposed,VBD,O
spontaneous,JJ,O
order,NN,O
",",",",O
whereby,WRB,O
organization,NN,O
emerges,VBZ,O
without,IN,O
central,JJ,O
authority,NN,O
",",",",O
a,DT,O
"""",LQU,O
positive,JJ,O
anarchy,NN,O
"""",RQU,O
where,WRB,O
order,NN,O
arises,VBZ,O
when,WRB,O
everybody,DT,O
does,VBZ,O
"""",LQU,O
what,WP,O
he,PRP,O
wishes,VBZ,O
and,CC,O
only,RB,O
what,WP,O
he,PRP,O
wishes,VBZ,O
"""",RQU,O
and,CC,O
where,WRB,O
"""",LQU,O
business,NN,O
transactions,NNS,O
alone,RB,O
produce,VBP,O
the,DT,O
social,JJ,O
order,NN,O
.,.,O
"""",RQU,O
Godwin,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
a,DT,O
philosophical,JJ,O
anarchist,NN,O
",",",",O
from,IN,O
a,DT,O
rationalist,NN,O
and,CC,O
utilitarian,JJ,O
basis,NN,O
opposed,VBD,O
revolutionary,JJ,O
action,NN,O
and,CC,O
saw,VBD,O
a,DT,O
minimal,JJ,O
state,NN,O
as,IN,O
a,DT,O
present,JJ,O
"""",LQU,O
necessary,JJ,O
evil,NN,O
"""",RQU,O
that,WDT,O
would,MD,O
become,VB,O
increasingly,RB,O
irrelevant,JJ,O
and,CC,O
powerless,JJ,O
by,IN,O
the,DT,O
gradual,JJ,O
spread,NN,O
of,IN,O
knowledge,NN,O
.,.,O
Godwin,NNP,I-PER
advocated,VBD,O
extreme,JJ,O
individualism,NN,O
",",",",O
proposing,VBG,O
that,IN,O
all,DT,O
cooperation,NN,O
in,IN,O
labour,NN,O
be,VB,O
eliminated,VBN,O
on,IN,O
the,DT,O
premise,NN,O
that,IN,O
this,DT,O
would,MD,O
be,VB,O
most,RBS,O
conducive,JJ,O
with,IN,O
the,DT,O
general,JJ,O
good,NN,O
.,.,O
Godwin,NNP,I-PER
opposed,VBD,O
government,NN,O
because,IN,O
he,PRP,O
saw,VBD,O
it,PRP,O
as,IN,O
infringing,VBG,O
on,IN,O
the,DT,O
individual,NN,O
's,POS,O
right,NN,O
to,TO,O
"""",LQU,O
private,JJ,O
judgement,NN,O
"""",RQU,O
to,TO,O
determine,VB,O
which,WDT,O
actions,NNS,O
most,RBS,O
maximise,JJ,O
utility,NN,O
",",",",O
but,CC,O
also,RB,O
makes,VBZ,O
a,DT,O
critique,NN,O
of,IN,O
all,DT,O
authority,NN,O
over,IN,O
the,DT,O
individual,NN,O
's,POS,O
judgement,NN,O
.,.,O
This,DT,O
aspect,NN,O
of,IN,O
Godwin,NNP,I-PER
's,POS,O
philosophy,NN,O
",",",",O
stripped,VBN,O
of,IN,O
utilitarian,JJ,O
motivations,NNS,O
",",",",O
was,VBD,O
developed,VBN,O
into,IN,O
a,DT,O
more,RBR,O
extreme,JJ,O
form,NN,O
later,RB,O
by,IN,O
Stirner,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
Stirner,NNP,I-PER
's,POS,O
The,DT,I-MISC
Ego,NNP,I-MISC
and,CC,I-MISC
Its,PRP$,I-MISC
Own,NNP,I-MISC
",",",",O
published,VBN,O
in,IN,O
1844,CD,O
",",",",O
is,VBZ,O
a,DT,O
founding,JJ,O
text,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
philosophy,NN,O
.,.,O
To,TO,O
Stirner,VB,I-PER
",",",",O
rights,NNS,O
were,VBD,O
spooks,NNS,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
mind,NN,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
he,PRP,O
held,VBD,O
that,IN,O
society,NN,O
does,VBZ,O
not,RB,O
exist,VB,O
but,CC,O
"""",LQU,O
the,DT,O
individuals,NNS,O
are,VBP,O
its,PRP$,O
reality,NN,O
"""",RQU,O
.,.,O
Stirner,NNP,I-PER
's,POS,O
philosophy,NN,O
has,VBZ,O
been,VBN,O
seen,VBN,O
as,IN,O
a,DT,O
precedent,NN,O
of,IN,O
existentialism,NN,O
with,IN,O
other,JJ,O
thinkers,NNS,O
like,IN,O
Friedrich,NNP,I-PER
Nietzsche,NNP,I-PER
and,CC,O
Søren,NNP,I-PER
Kierkegaard,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
Collectivist,NNP,O
anarchism,NN,O
",",",",O
also,RB,O
referred,VBD,O
to,TO,O
as,IN,O
"""",LQU,O
revolutionary,JJ,O
socialism,NN,O
"""",RQU,O
or,CC,O
a,DT,O
form,NN,O
of,IN,O
such,JJ,O
",",",",O
is,VBZ,O
a,DT,O
revolutionary,JJ,O
form,NN,O
of,IN,O
anarchism,NN,O
",",",",O
commonly,RB,O
associated,VBN,O
with,IN,O
Mikhail,NNP,I-PER
Bakunin,NNP,I-PER
and,CC,O
Johann,NNP,I-PER
Most,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
It,PRP,O
was,VBD,O
inspired,VBN,O
by,IN,O
the,DT,O
late,JJ,O
19th,JJ,O
century,NN,O
writings,NNS,O
of,IN,O
early,JJ,O
feminist,JJ,O
anarchists,NNS,O
such,JJ,O
as,IN,O
Lucy,NNP,I-PER
Parsons,NNPS,I-PER
",",",",O
Emma,NNP,I-PER
Goldman,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
Voltairine,NNP,I-PER
de,NNP,I-PER
Cleyre,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
and,CC,O
Dora,NNP,I-PER
Marsden,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
It,PRP,O
developed,VBD,O
"""",LQU,O
mostly,RB,O
in,IN,O
Holland,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
Britain,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
and,CC,O
the,DT,O
U.S.,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
before,IN,O
and,CC,O
during,IN,O
the,DT,O
Second,JJ,I-MISC
World,NNP,I-MISC
War,NNP,I-MISC
"""",RQU,O
.,.,O
Another,DT,O
recent,JJ,O
form,NN,O
of,IN,O
anarchism,NN,O
critical,JJ,O
of,IN,O
formal,JJ,O
anarchist,NN,O
movements,NNS,O
is,VBZ,O
insurrectionary,JJ,O
anarchism,NN,O
",",",",O
which,WDT,O
advocates,VBZ,O
informal,JJ,O
organization,NN,O
and,CC,O
active,JJ,O
resistance,NN,O
to,TO,O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
;,;,O
its,PRP$,O
proponents,NNS,O
include,VBP,O
Wolfi,NNP,I-PER
Landstreicher,NNP,I-PER
and,CC,O
Alfredo,NNP,I-PER
M.,NNP,I-PER
Bonanno,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
Free,JJ,O
love,NN,O
advocates,NNS,O
sometimes,RB,O
traced,VBD,O
their,PRP$,O
roots,NNS,O
back,RB,O
to,TO,O
Josiah,NNP,I-PER
Warren,NNP,I-PER
and,CC,O
to,TO,O
experimental,JJ,O
communities,NNS,O
",",",",O
viewed,VBD,O
sexual,JJ,O
freedom,NN,O
as,IN,O
a,DT,O
clear,JJ,O
",",",",O
direct,JJ,O
expression,NN,O
of,IN,O
an,DT,O
individual,NN,O
's,POS,O
self-ownership,NN,O
.,.,O
In,IN,O
New,NNP,I-LOC
York,NNP,I-LOC
's,POS,O
Greenwich,NNP,I-LOC
Village,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
bohemian,JJ,O
feminists,NNS,O
and,CC,O
socialists,NNS,O
advocated,VBN,O
self-realisation,NN,O
and,CC,O
pleasure,NN,O
for,IN,O
women,NNS,O
(,LRB,O
and,CC,O
also,RB,O
men,NNS,O
),RRB,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
here,RB,O
and,CC,O
now,RB,O
.,.,O
They,PRP,O
encouraged,VBD,O
playing,VBG,O
with,IN,O
sexual,JJ,O
roles,NNS,O
and,CC,O
sexuality,NN,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
the,DT,O
openly,RB,O
bisexual,JJ,O
radical,JJ,O
Edna,NNP,I-PER
St.,NNP,I-PER
Vincent,NNP,I-PER
Millay,NNP,I-PER
and,CC,O
the,DT,O
lesbian,JJ,O
anarchist,NN,O
Margaret,NNP,I-PER
Anderson,NNP,I-PER
were,VBD,O
prominent,JJ,O
among,IN,O
them,PRP,O
.,.,O
"""",RQU,O
Max,NNP,I-PER
Stirner,NNP,I-PER
wrote,VBD,O
in,IN,O
1842,CD,O
a,DT,O
long,JJ,O
essay,NN,O
on,IN,O
education,NN,O
called,VBN,O
The,DT,I-MISC
False,NNP,I-MISC
Principle,NN,I-MISC
of,IN,I-MISC
our,PRP$,I-MISC
Education,NN,I-MISC
.,.,O
In,IN,O
it,PRP,O
Stirner,JJR,I-PER
names,NNS,O
his,PRP$,O
educational,JJ,O
principle,NN,O
"""",LQU,O
"personalist,",VBZ,O
"""",RQU,O
explaining,VBG,O
that,DT,O
self-understanding,NN,O
consists,VBZ,O
in,IN,O
hourly,JJ,O
self-creation,NN,O
.,.,O
"""",RQU,O
The,DT,O
first,NN,O
of,IN,O
these,DT,O
was,VBD,O
started,VBN,O
in,IN,O
New,NNP,I-LOC
York,NNP,I-LOC
City,NNP,I-LOC
in,IN,O
1911,CD,O
.,.,O
Summerhill,NNP,I-ORG
is,VBZ,O
often,RB,O
cited,VBN,O
as,IN,O
an,DT,O
example,NN,O
of,IN,O
anarchism,NN,O
in,IN,O
practice,NN,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
term,NN,O
deschooling,NN,O
was,VBD,O
popularized,VBN,O
by,IN,O
Ivan,NNP,I-PER
Illich,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
who,WP,O
argued,VBD,O
that,IN,O
the,DT,O
school,NN,O
as,IN,O
an,DT,O
institution,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
dysfunctional,JJ,O
for,IN,O
self-determined,JJ,O
learning,NN,O
and,CC,O
serves,VBZ,O
the,DT,O
creation,NN,O
of,IN,O
a,DT,O
consumer,NN,O
society,NN,O
instead,RB,O
.,.,O
According,VBG,O
to,TO,O
Luther,NNP,I-PER
's,POS,O
notetaker,NN,O
Mathesius,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
Luther,NNP,I-PER
thought,VBD,O
the,DT,O
boy,NN,O
was,VBD,O
a,DT,O
soulless,JJ,O
mass,NN,O
of,IN,O
flesh,NN,O
possessed,VBN,O
by,IN,O
the,DT,O
devil,NN,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
suggested,VBD,O
that,IN,O
he,PRP,O
be,VB,O
suffocated,VBN,O
.,.,O
Kanner,NNP,I-PER
's,POS,O
reuse,NN,O
of,IN,O
autism,NN,O
led,VBD,O
to,TO,O
decades,NNS,O
of,IN,O
confused,JJ,O
terminology,NN,O
like,IN,O
infantile,JJ,O
schizophrenia,NN,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
child,NN,O
psychiatry,NN,O
's,POS,O
focus,NN,O
on,IN,O
maternal,JJ,O
deprivation,NN,O
led,VBD,O
to,TO,O
misconceptions,NNS,O
of,IN,O
autism,NN,O
as,IN,O
an,DT,O
infant,NN,O
's,POS,O
response,NN,O
to,TO,O
"""",LQU,O
refrigerator,NN,O
mothers,NNS,O
"""",RQU,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
Internet,NNP,I-MISC
has,VBZ,O
helped,VBN,O
autistic,JJ,O
individuals,NNS,O
bypass,VBP,O
nonverbal,JJ,O
cues,NNS,O
and,CC,O
emotional,JJ,O
sharing,NN,O
that,IN,O
they,PRP,O
find,VBP,O
so,SO,O
hard,JJ,O
to,TO,O
deal,VB,O
with,IN,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
has,VBZ,O
given,VBN,O
them,PRP,O
a,DT,O
way,NN,O
to,TO,O
form,VB,O
online,JJ,O
communities,NNS,O
and,CC,O
work,NN,O
remotely,RB,O
.,.,O
Another,DT,O
notable,JJ,O
high,JJ,O
albedo,NN,O
body,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
Eris,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
with,IN,O
an,DT,O
albedo,NN,O
of,IN,O
0.86,CD,O
.,.,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
(,LRB,O
i,NNP,O
i,NNP,O
i,NNP,O
/,NNP,O
l,NNP,O
ə,NNP,O
ˈ,NNP,O
b,NN,O
æ,NN,O
m,NN,O
ə,NNP,O
/,NNP,O
),RRB,O
is,VBZ,O
a,DT,O
state,NN,O
located,VBN,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
southeastern,JJ,O
region,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
United,NNP,I-LOC
States,NNPS,I-LOC
of,IN,I-LOC
America,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
ranks,VBZ,O
30th,JJ,O
in,IN,O
total,JJ,O
land,NN,O
area,NN,O
and,CC,O
ranks,VBZ,O
second,JJ,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
size,NN,O
of,IN,O
its,PRP$,O
inland,NN,O
waterways,NNS,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
capital,NN,O
of,IN,O
Ala.,NNP,I-LOC
is,VBZ,O
Montgomery,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
The,DT,O
largest,JJS,O
city,NN,O
by,IN,O
population,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
Birmingham,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
The,DT,O
largest,JJS,O
city,NN,O
by,IN,O
total,JJ,O
land,NN,O
area,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
Huntsville,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
Scholars,NNS,O
believe,VBP,O
the,DT,O
word,NN,O
comes,VBZ,O
from,IN,O
the,DT,O
Choctaw,NNP,I-MISC
alba,NN,O
(,LRB,O
meaning,VBG,O
"""",LQU,O
plants,NNS,O
"""",RQU,O
or,CC,O
"""",LQU,O
weeds,NNS,O
"""",RQU,O
),RRB,O
and,CC,O
amo,NN,O
(,LRB,O
meaning,VBG,O
"""",LQU,O
to,TO,O
cut,VB,O
"""",RQU,O
",",",",O
"""",LQU,O
to,TO,O
trim,VB,O
"""",RQU,O
",",",",O
or,CC,O
"""",LQU,O
to,TO,O
gather,VB,O
"""",RQU,O
),RRB,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
economy,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
central,JJ,O
"""",LQU,O
Black,NNP,I-LOC
Belt,NNP,I-LOC
"""",RQU,O
was,VBD,O
built,VBN,O
around,IN,O
large,JJ,O
cotton,NN,O
plantations,NNS,O
whose,WP$,O
owners,NNS,O
built,VBD,O
their,PRP$,O
wealth,NN,O
on,IN,O
slave,JJ,O
labor,NN,O
.,.,O
While,IN,O
few,JJ,O
battles,NNS,O
were,VBD,O
fought,VBN,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
",",",",O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
contributed,VBD,O
about,IN,O
"120,000",CD,O
soldiers,NNS,O
to,TO,O
the,DT,O
American,NNP,I-MISC
Civil,NNP,I-MISC
War,NNP,I-MISC
.,.,O
After,IN,O
the,DT,O
Civil,NNP,I-MISC
War,NNP,I-MISC
",",",",O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
was,VBD,O
still,RB,O
chiefly,RB,O
agricultural,JJ,O
",",",",O
with,IN,O
an,DT,O
economy,NN,O
tied,VBN,O
to,TO,O
cotton,NN,O
.,.,O
In,IN,O
1900,CD,O
",",",",O
fourteen,CD,O
Black,NNP,I-LOC
Belt,NNP,I-LOC
counties,NNS,O
had,VBD,O
more,JJR,O
than,IN,O
"79,000",CD,O
voters,NNS,O
on,IN,O
the,DT,O
rolls,NNS,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
Voting,NNP,I-MISC
Rights,NNP,I-MISC
Act,NNP,I-MISC
of,IN,I-MISC
1965,CD,I-MISC
also,RB,O
protected,VBD,O
the,DT,O
suffrage,NN,O
of,IN,O
poor,JJ,O
whites,NNS,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
population,NN,O
growth,NN,O
rate,NN,O
in,IN,O
Ala.,NNP,I-LOC
dropped,VBD,O
by,IN,O
nearly,RB,O
half,NN,O
from,IN,O
1910,CD,O
--,:,O
1920,CD,O
",",",",O
reflecting,VBG,O
the,DT,O
effect,NN,O
of,IN,O
emigration,NN,O
.,.,O
At,IN,O
the,DT,O
same,JJ,O
time,NN,O
",",",",O
many,JJ,O
rural,JJ,O
whites,NNS,O
and,CC,O
blacks,NNS,O
migrated,VBD,O
to,TO,O
the,DT,O
city,NN,O
of,IN,O
Birmingham,NNP,I-LOC
for,IN,O
work,NN,O
in,IN,O
new,JJ,O
industrial,JJ,O
jobs,NNS,O
.,.,O
It,PRP,O
experienced,VBD,O
such,JJ,O
rapid,JJ,O
growth,NN,O
that,IN,O
it,PRP,O
was,VBD,O
nicknamed,VBN,O
"""",LQU,O
The,DT,O
Magic,NNP,I-LOC
City,NNP,I-LOC
"""",RQU,O
.,.,O
In,IN,O
addition,NN,O
",",",",O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
legislature,NN,O
gerrymandered,VBD,O
the,DT,O
few,JJ,O
Birmingham,NNP,I-LOC
legislative,JJ,O
seats,NNS,O
to,TO,O
ensure,VB,O
election,NN,O
by,IN,O
persons,NNS,O
living,VBG,O
outside,IN,O
Birmingham,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
One,CD,O
result,NN,O
was,VBD,O
that,IN,O
Jefferson,NNP,I-LOC
County,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
containing,VBG,O
Birmingham,NNP,I-LOC
's,POS,O
industrial,JJ,O
and,CC,O
economic,JJ,O
powerhouse,NN,O
",",",",O
contributed,VBD,O
more,JJR,O
than,IN,O
one-third,NN,O
of,IN,O
all,DT,O
tax,NN,O
revenue,NN,O
to,TO,O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
",",",",O
but,CC,O
did,VBD,O
not,RB,O
received,VBN,O
a,DT,O
proportional,JJ,O
amount,NN,O
in,IN,O
services,NNS,O
.,.,O
A,DT,O
1960,CD,O
study,NN,O
noted,VBD,O
that,IN,O
because,IN,O
of,IN,O
rural,JJ,O
domination,NN,O
",",",",O
"""",LQU,O
A,DT,O
minority,NN,O
of,IN,O
about,IN,O
25,CD,O
per,IN,O
cent,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
total,JJ,O
state,NN,O
population,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
in,IN,O
majority,NN,O
control,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
Alabama,NNP,I-ORG
legislature,NN,I-ORG
.,.,O
"""",RQU,O
These,DT,O
factors,NNS,O
created,VBD,O
a,DT,O
longstanding,JJ,O
tradition,NN,O
that,IN,O
any,DT,O
candidate,NN,O
who,WP,O
wanted,VBD,O
to,TO,O
be,VB,O
viable,JJ,O
with,IN,O
white,JJ,O
voters,NNS,O
had,VBD,O
to,TO,O
run,VB,O
as,IN,O
a,DT,O
Democrat,NNP,I-ORG
regardless,RB,O
of,IN,O
political,JJ,O
beliefs,NNS,O
.,.,O
Industrial,JJ,O
development,NN,O
related,VBN,O
to,TO,O
the,DT,O
demands,NNS,O
of,IN,O
World,NNP,I-MISC
War,NNP,I-MISC
II,NNP,I-MISC
brought,VBD,O
prosperity,NN,O
.,.,O
In,IN,O
the,DT,O
1960s,NNS,O
under,IN,O
Governor,NNP,O
George,NNP,I-PER
Wallace,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
many,JJ,O
whites,NNS,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
opposed,VBD,O
integration,NN,O
efforts,NNS,O
.,.,O
After,IN,O
1972,CD,O
",",",",O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
's,POS,O
white,JJ,O
voters,NNS,O
shifted,VBD,O
much,RB,O
of,IN,O
their,PRP$,O
support,NN,O
to,TO,O
Republican,NNP,I-MISC
candidates,NNS,O
in,IN,O
presidential,JJ,O
elections,NNS,O
(,LRB,O
as,IN,O
also,RB,O
occurred,VBD,O
in,IN,O
neighboring,VBG,O
southern,JJ,O
states,NNS,O
),RRB,O
.,.,O
Since,IN,O
1990,CD,O
the,DT,O
majority,NN,O
of,IN,O
whites,NNS,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
have,VBP,O
voted,VBN,O
increasingly,RB,O
Republican,JJ,I-MISC
in,IN,O
state,NN,O
elections,NNS,O
.,.,O
Democrats,NNS,I-ORG
are,VBP,O
still,RB,O
the,DT,O
majority,NN,O
party,NN,O
in,IN,O
both,DT,O
houses,NNS,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
legislature,NN,O
.,.,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
has,VBZ,O
coastline,VBN,O
at,IN,O
the,DT,O
Gulf,NNP,I-LOC
of,IN,I-LOC
Mexico,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
extreme,JJ,O
southern,JJ,O
edge,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
.,.,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
ranges,NNS,O
in,IN,O
elevation,NN,O
from,IN,O
sea,NN,O
level,NN,O
at,IN,O
Mobile,NNP,I-LOC
Bay,NNP,I-LOC
to,TO,O
over,IN,O
"1,800",CD,O
feet,NNS,O
(,LRB,O
550,CD,O
m,NN,O
),RRB,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
Appalachian,JJ,I-LOC
Mountains,NNS,I-LOC
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
northeast,NN,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
highest,JJS,O
point,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
Mount,NNP,I-LOC
Cheaha,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
at,IN,O
a,DT,O
height,NN,O
of,IN,O
2407,CD,O
ft,NN,O
(,LRB,O
734,CD,O
m,NN,O
),RRB,O
.,.,O
Ala.,NNP,I-LOC
's,POS,O
land,NN,O
consists,VBZ,O
of,IN,O
22,CD,O
million,CD,O
acres,NNS,O
(,LRB,O
89000,CD,O
km,NN,O
2,CD,O
),RRB,O
of,IN,O
forest,NN,O
or,CC,O
67,CD,O
%,NN,O
of,IN,O
total,JJ,O
land,NN,O
area,NN,O
.,.,O
Areas,NNP,O
in,IN,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
administered,VBN,O
by,IN,O
the,DT,O
National,NNP,I-ORG
Park,NNP,I-ORG
Service,NNP,I-ORG
include,VBP,O
Horseshoe,NNP,I-LOC
Bend,NNP,I-LOC
National,NNP,I-LOC
Military,NNP,I-LOC
Park,NNP,I-LOC
near,IN,O
Alexander,NNP,I-LOC
City,NNP,I-LOC
;,;,O
Little,NNP,I-LOC
River,NNP,I-LOC
Canyon,NNP,I-LOC
National,NNP,I-LOC
Preserve,NNP,I-LOC
near,IN,O
Fort,NNP,I-LOC
Payne,NNP,I-LOC
;,;,O
Russell,NNP,I-LOC
Cave,NNP,I-LOC
National,NNP,I-LOC
Monument,NNP,I-LOC
in,IN,O
Bridgeport,NNP,I-LOC
;,;,O
Tuskegee,NNP,I-LOC
Airmen,NNP,I-LOC
National,NNP,I-LOC
Historic,NNP,I-LOC
Site,NNP,I-LOC
in,IN,O
Tuskegee,NNP,I-LOC
;,;,O
and,CC,O
Tuskegee,NNP,I-ORG
Institute,NNP,I-ORG
National,NNP,I-ORG
Historic,NNP,I-ORG
Site,NNP,I-ORG
near,IN,O
Tuskegee,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
A,DT,O
notable,JJ,O
natural,JJ,O
wonder,NN,O
in,IN,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
is,VBZ,O
"""",LQU,I-LOC
Natural,NNP,I-LOC
Bridge,NNP,I-LOC
"""",RQU,I-LOC
rock,NN,O
",",",",O
the,DT,O
longest,JJS,O
natural,JJ,O
bridge,NN,O
east,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
Rockies,NNPS,I-LOC
",",",",O
located,VBN,O
just,RB,O
south,RB,O
of,IN,O
Haleyville,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
in,IN,O
Winston,NNP,I-LOC
County,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
A,DT,O
5-mile,JJ,O
(,LRB,O
8,CD,O
km,NN,O
),RRB,O
-wide,JJ,O
meteorite,JJ,O
impact,NN,O
crater,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
located,VBN,O
in,IN,O
Elmore,NNP,I-LOC
County,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
just,RB,O
north,NN,O
of,IN,O
Montgomery,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
Temperatures,NNS,O
tend,VBP,O
to,TO,O
be,VB,O
warmer,NN,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
southern,JJ,O
part,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
with,IN,O
its,PRP$,O
proximity,NN,O
to,TO,O
the,DT,O
Gulf,NNP,I-LOC
of,IN,I-LOC
Mexico,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
while,IN,O
the,DT,O
northern,JJ,O
parts,NNS,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
",",",",O
especially,RB,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
Appalachian,JJ,I-LOC
Mountains,NNS,I-LOC
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
northeast,NN,O
",",",",O
tend,VBP,O
to,TO,O
be,VB,O
slightly,RB,O
cooler,JJR,O
.,.,O
Generally,RB,O
",",",",O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
has,VBZ,O
very,RB,O
hot,JJ,O
summers,NNS,O
and,CC,O
mild,JJ,O
winters,NNS,O
with,IN,O
copious,JJ,O
precipitation,NN,O
throughout,IN,O
the,DT,O
year,NN,O
.,.,O
Ala.,NNP,I-LOC
is,VBZ,O
also,RB,O
prone,JJ,O
to,TO,O
tropical,JJ,O
storms,NNS,O
and,CC,O
even,RB,O
hurricanes,NNS,O
.,.,O
Areas,NNS,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
far,RB,O
away,RB,O
from,IN,O
the,DT,O
Gulf,NNP,I-LOC
are,VBP,O
not,RB,O
immune,JJ,O
to,TO,O
the,DT,O
effects,NNS,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
storms,NNS,O
",",",",O
which,WDT,O
often,RB,O
dump,VBP,O
tremendous,JJ,O
amounts,NNS,O
of,IN,O
rain,NN,O
as,IN,O
they,PRP,O
move,VBP,O
inland,RB,O
and,CC,O
weaken,VB,O
.,.,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
ranks,VBZ,O
seventh,JJ,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
number,NN,O
of,IN,O
deaths,NNS,O
from,IN,O
lightning,NN,O
and,CC,O
ninth,NN,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
number,NN,O
of,IN,O
deaths,NNS,O
from,IN,O
lightning,VBG,O
strikes,NNS,O
per,IN,O
capita,NN,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
Super,NNP,I-MISC
Outbreak,NNP,I-MISC
in,IN,O
March,NNP,O
1974,CD,O
",",",",O
badly,RB,O
affected,VBN,O
Ala.,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
Although,IN,O
snow,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
a,DT,O
rare,JJ,O
event,NN,O
in,IN,O
much,NN,O
of,IN,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
areas,NNS,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
north,NN,O
of,IN,O
Montgomery,NNP,I-LOC
may,MD,O
receive,VB,O
a,DT,O
dusting,NN,O
of,IN,O
snow,NN,O
a,DT,O
few,JJ,O
times,NNS,O
every,DT,O
winter,NN,O
",",",",O
with,IN,O
an,DT,O
occasional,JJ,O
moderately,RB,O
heavy,JJ,O
snowfall,NN,O
every,DT,O
few,JJ,O
years,NNS,O
.,.,O
For,IN,O
example,NN,O
",",",",O
the,DT,O
annual,JJ,O
average,NN,O
snowfall,NN,O
for,IN,O
the,DT,O
Birmingham,NNP,I-LOC
area,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
2,CD,O
inches,NNS,O
per,IN,O
year,NN,O
.,.,O
In,IN,O
the,DT,O
southern,JJ,O
Gulf,NNP,I-LOC
coast,NN,O
",",",",O
snowfall,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
less,RBR,O
frequent,JJ,O
",",",",O
sometimes,RB,O
going,VBG,O
several,JJ,O
years,NNS,O
without,IN,O
any,DT,O
snowfall,NN,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
United,NNP,I-ORG
States,NNPS,I-ORG
Census,NNP,I-ORG
Bureau,NNP,I-ORG
",",",",O
as,IN,O
of,IN,O
July,NNP,O
1,CD,O
",",",",O
2008,CD,O
",",",",O
estimated,VBN,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
's,POS,O
population,NN,O
at,IN,O
"4,661,900",CD,O
",",",",O
which,WDT,O
represents,VBZ,O
an,DT,O
increase,NN,O
of,IN,O
"214,545",CD,O
",",",",O
or,CC,O
4.8,CD,O
%,NN,O
",",",",O
since,IN,O
the,DT,O
last,JJ,O
census,NN,O
in,IN,O
2000,CD,O
.,.,O
Working,NNP,O
with,IN,O
Auburn,NNP,I-ORG
University,NNP,I-ORG
",",",",O
the,DT,O
tribe,NN,O
has,VBZ,O
begun,VBN,O
a,DT,O
revival,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
Cherokee,NNP,I-ORG
language,NN,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
Mobile,NNP,I-LOC
area,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
notable,JJ,O
for,IN,O
its,PRP$,O
large,JJ,O
percentage,NN,O
of,IN,O
Catholics,NNPS,I-MISC
",",",",O
owing,VBG,O
to,TO,O
the,DT,O
area,NN,O
's,POS,O
founding,NN,O
as,IN,O
part,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
French,JJ,I-MISC
colony,NN,O
of,IN,O
La,NNP,I-LOC
Louisiane,NNP,I-LOC
and,CC,O
later,RB,O
history,NN,O
under,IN,O
Spanish,JJ,I-MISC
rule,NN,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
Southern,NNP,I-ORG
Baptist,NNP,I-ORG
Convention,NNP,I-ORG
has,VBZ,O
the,DT,O
highest,JJS,O
number,NN,O
of,IN,O
adherents,NNS,O
in,IN,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
with,IN,O
"1,380,121",CD,O
",",",",O
followed,VBN,O
by,IN,O
the,DT,O
United,NNP,I-ORG
Methodist,NNP,I-ORG
Church,NNP,I-ORG
with,IN,O
"327,734",CD,O
members,NNS,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
the,DT,O
Catholic,NNP,I-PER
Church,NNP,I-PER
with,IN,O
"150,647",CD,O
adherents,NNS,O
.,.,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
's,POS,O
agricultural,JJ,O
outputs,NNS,O
include,VBP,O
poultry,NN,O
and,CC,O
eggs,NNS,O
",",",",O
cattle,NNS,O
",",",",O
plant,NN,O
nursery,NN,O
items,NNS,O
",",",",O
peanuts,NNS,O
",",",",O
cotton,NN,O
",",",",O
grains,NNS,O
such,JJ,O
as,IN,O
corn,NN,O
and,CC,O
sorghum,NN,O
",",",",O
vegetables,NNS,O
",",",",O
milk,NN,O
",",",",O
soybeans,NNS,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
peaches,NNS,O
.,.,O
Ala.,NNP,I-LOC
is,VBZ,O
part,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
largest,JJS,O
industrial,JJ,O
growth,NN,O
corridor,NN,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
nation,NN,O
.,.,O
In,IN,O
the,DT,O
1970s,NNS,O
and,CC,O
1980s,NNS,O
",",",",O
Birmingham,NNP,I-LOC
's,POS,O
economy,NN,O
was,VBD,O
transformed,VBN,O
by,IN,O
the,DT,O
University,NNP,I-ORG
of,IN,I-ORG
Alabama,NNP,I-ORG
at,IN,I-ORG
Birmingham,NNP,I-ORG
(,LRB,O
UAB,NNP,I-ORG
),RRB,O
's,POS,O
investments,NNS,O
in,IN,O
bio-technology,NN,O
and,CC,O
medical,JJ,O
research,NN,O
.,.,O
UAB,NNP,I-ORG
is,VBZ,O
now,RB,O
the,DT,O
area,NN,O
's,POS,O
largest,JJS,O
employer,NN,O
and,CC,O
the,DT,O
largest,JJS,O
in,IN,O
Ala.,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
with,IN,O
a,DT,O
workforce,NN,O
of,IN,O
about,IN,O
"20,000",CD,O
.,.,O
In,IN,O
November,NNP,O
2006,CD,O
",",",",O
Regions,NNP,I-ORG
Financial,NNP,I-ORG
completed,VBD,O
its,PRP$,O
merger,NN,O
with,IN,O
AmSouth,NNP,I-ORG
Bancorporation,NNP,I-ORG
",",",",O
which,WDT,O
was,VBD,O
also,RB,O
headquartered,VBN,O
in,IN,O
Birmingham,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
SouthTrust,NNP,I-ORG
Corporation,NNP,I-ORG
",",",",O
another,DT,O
large,JJ,O
bank,NN,O
headquartered,VBD,O
in,IN,O
Birmingham,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
was,VBD,O
acquired,VBN,O
by,IN,O
Wachovia,NNP,I-ORG
in,IN,O
2004,CD,O
for,IN,O
$,$,O
14.3,CD,O
billion,CD,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
city,NN,O
still,RB,O
has,VBZ,O
major,JJ,O
operations,NNS,O
for,IN,O
Wachovia,NNP,I-ORG
and,CC,O
its,PRP$,O
now,RB,O
post-operating,JJ,O
bank,NN,O
Wells,NNP,I-ORG
Fargo,NNP,I-ORG
",",",",O
which,WDT,O
includes,VBZ,O
a,DT,O
regional,JJ,O
headquarters,NN,O
",",",",O
a,DT,O
operations,NNS,O
center,NN,O
campus,NN,O
and,CC,O
a,DT,O
$,$,O
400,CD,O
million,CD,O
dollar,NN,O
data,NNS,O
center,NN,O
.,.,O
Birmingham,NNP,I-LOC
also,RB,O
serves,VBZ,O
as,IN,O
the,DT,O
headquarters,NN,O
for,IN,O
several,JJ,O
large,JJ,O
investment,NN,O
management,NN,O
companies,NNS,O
",",",",O
including,VBG,O
Harbert,NNP,I-ORG
Management,NNP,I-ORG
Corporation,NNP,I-ORG
.,.,O
Major,JJ,O
insurance,NN,O
providers,NNS,O
include,VBP,O
Protective,NNP,I-ORG
Life,NNP,I-ORG
",",",",O
Infinity,NNP,I-ORG
Property,NNP,I-ORG
&,CC,I-ORG
Casualty,NNP,I-ORG
",",",",O
Liberty,NNP,I-ORG
National,NNP,I-ORG
Life,NNP,I-ORG
Insurance,NNP,I-ORG
Company,NNP,I-ORG
and,CC,O
ProAssurance,NNP,I-ORG
.,.,O
Torchmark,NNP,I-ORG
Corporation,NNP,I-ORG
was,VBD,O
headquartered,VBN,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
city,NN,O
until,IN,O
2006,CD,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
still,RB,O
maintains,VBZ,O
its,PRP$,O
largest,JJS,O
operation,NN,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
city,NN,O
.,.,O
Birmingham,NNP,I-LOC
is,VBZ,O
also,RB,O
a,DT,O
powerhouse,NN,O
of,IN,O
construction,NN,O
and,CC,O
engineering,NN,O
companies,NNS,O
.,.,O
Huntsville,NNP,I-LOC
has,VBZ,O
a,DT,O
technology-driven,JJ,O
economy,NN,O
",",",",O
a,DT,O
result,NN,O
of,IN,O
NASA,NNP,I-ORG
's,POS,O
Marshall,NNP,I-LOC
Space,NNP,I-LOC
Flight,NNP,I-LOC
Center,NNP,I-LOC
and,CC,O
the,DT,O
Redstone,NNP,I-LOC
Arsenal,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
Huntsville,NNP,I-LOC
's,POS,O
main,JJ,O
economic,JJ,O
influence,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
derived,VBN,O
from,IN,O
aerospace,NN,O
and,CC,O
military,JJ,O
technology,NN,O
.,.,O
Sanmina-SCI,NNP,I-ORG
has,VBZ,O
a,DT,O
large,JJ,O
presence,NN,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
area,NN,O
.,.,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
levies,VBZ,O
a,DT,O
2,CD,O
",",",",O
4,CD,O
",",",",O
or,CC,O
5,CD,O
percent,NN,O
personal,JJ,O
income,NN,O
tax,NN,O
",",",",O
depending,VBG,O
upon,IN,O
the,DT,O
amount,NN,O
earned,VBN,O
and,CC,O
filing,NN,O
status,NN,O
",",",",O
though,IN,O
taxpayers,NNS,O
can,MD,O
deduct,VB,O
their,PRP$,O
federal,JJ,O
income,NN,O
tax,NN,O
from,IN,O
their,PRP$,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
state,NN,O
tax,NN,O
.,.,O
For,IN,O
example,NN,O
",",",",O
the,DT,O
total,JJ,O
sales,NNS,O
tax,NN,O
rate,NN,O
in,IN,O
Mobile,NNP,I-LOC
is,VBZ,O
9,CD,O
%,NN,O
and,CC,O
there,EX,O
is,VBZ,O
an,DT,O
additional,JJ,O
restaurant,NN,O
tax,NN,O
of,IN,O
1,CD,O
%,NN,O
",",",",O
which,WDT,O
means,VBZ,O
that,IN,O
a,DT,O
diner,NN,O
in,IN,O
Mobile,NNP,I-LOC
would,MD,O
pay,VB,O
a,DT,O
10,CD,O
%,NN,O
tax,NN,O
on,IN,O
a,DT,O
meal,NN,O
.,.,O
Sales,NNS,O
and,CC,O
excise,NN,O
taxes,NNS,O
in,IN,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
account,NN,O
for,IN,O
51,CD,O
percent,NN,O
of,IN,O
all,DT,O
state,NN,O
and,CC,O
local,JJ,O
revenue,NN,O
",",",",O
compared,VBN,O
with,IN,O
an,DT,O
average,NN,O
of,IN,O
about,IN,O
36,CD,O
percent,NN,O
nationwide,NN,O
.,.,O
Ala.,NNP,I-LOC
is,VBZ,O
also,RB,O
one,CD,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
few,JJ,O
remaining,VBG,O
states,NNS,O
that,WDT,O
levies,VBZ,O
a,DT,O
tax,NN,O
on,IN,O
food,NN,O
and,CC,O
medicine,NN,O
.,.,O
Ala.,NNP,I-LOC
's,POS,O
income,NN,O
tax,NN,O
on,IN,O
poor,JJ,O
working,VBG,O
families,NNS,O
is,VBZ,O
among,IN,O
the,DT,O
nation,NN,O
's,POS,O
very,RB,O
highest,JJS,O
.,.,O
[,NNP,O
citation,NN,O
needed,VBD,O
],NNP,O
Ala.,NNP,I-LOC
is,VBZ,O
the,DT,O
only,JJ,O
state,NN,O
that,WDT,O
levies,VBZ,O
income,NN,O
tax,NN,O
on,IN,O
a,DT,O
family,NN,O
of,IN,O
four,CD,O
with,IN,O
income,NN,O
as,RB,O
low,JJ,O
as,IN,O
$,$,O
"4,600",CD,O
",",",",O
which,WDT,O
is,VBZ,O
barely,RB,O
one-quarter,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
federal,JJ,O
poverty,NN,O
line,NN,O
.,.,O
[,NNP,O
citation,NN,O
needed,VBD,O
],NNP,O
Ala.,NNP,I-LOC
's,POS,O
threshold,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
the,DT,O
lowest,JJS,O
among,IN,O
the,DT,O
41,CD,O
states,NNS,O
and,CC,O
the,DT,O
District,NNP,I-LOC
of,IN,I-LOC
Columbia,NNP,I-LOC
with,IN,O
income,NN,O
taxes,NNS,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
overall,JJ,O
federal,JJ,O
",",",",O
state,NN,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
local,JJ,O
tax,NN,O
burden,NN,O
in,IN,O
Ala.,NNP,I-LOC
ranks,VBZ,O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
as,IN,O
the,DT,O
second,JJ,O
least,JJS,O
tax-burdened,JJ,O
state,NN,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
country,NN,O
.,.,O
For,IN,O
example,NN,O
",",",",O
in,IN,O
2003,CD,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
had,VBD,O
an,DT,O
annual,JJ,O
budget,NN,O
deficit,NN,O
as,RB,O
high,JJ,O
as,IN,O
$,$,O
670,CD,O
million,CD,O
.,.,O
When,WRB,O
completed,VBN,O
around,IN,O
2012,CD,O
it,PRP,O
will,MD,O
connect,VB,O
Birmingham,NNP,I-LOC
with,IN,O
Memphis,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
Tennessee,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
Major,JJ,O
airports,NNS,O
in,IN,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
include,VBP,O
Birmingham-Shuttlesworth,NNP,I-LOC
International,NNP,I-LOC
Airport,NNP,I-LOC
(,LRB,O
BHM,NNP,I-LOC
),RRB,O
",",",",O
Huntsville,NNP,I-LOC
International,NNP,I-LOC
Airport,NNP,I-LOC
(,LRB,O
HSV,NNP,I-LOC
),RRB,O
",",",",O
Dothan,NNP,I-LOC
Regional,NNP,I-LOC
Airport,NNP,I-LOC
(,LRB,O
DHN,NNP,I-LOC
),RRB,O
",",",",O
Mobile,NNP,I-LOC
Regional,NNP,I-LOC
Airport,NNP,I-LOC
(,LRB,O
MOB,NNP,I-LOC
),RRB,O
",",",",O
Montgomery,NNP,I-LOC
Regional,NNP,I-LOC
Airport,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
Muscle,NNP,I-LOC
Shoals,NNP,I-LOC
--,:,I-LOC
Northwest,NNP,I-LOC
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
Regional,NNP,I-LOC
Airport,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
Tuscaloosa,NNP,I-LOC
Regional,NNP,I-LOC
Airport,NNP,I-LOC
(,LRB,O
TCL,NNP,I-LOC
),RRB,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
Pryor,NNP,I-LOC
Field,NNP,I-LOC
Regional,NNP,I-LOC
Airport,NNP,I-LOC
(,LRB,O
DCU,NNP,I-LOC
),RRB,O
.,.,O
There,EX,O
is,VBZ,O
a,DT,O
significant,JJ,O
movement,NN,O
to,TO,O
rewrite,VB,O
and,CC,O
modernize,VB,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
's,POS,O
constitution,NN,O
.,.,O
This,DT,O
movement,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
based,VBN,O
upon,IN,O
the,DT,O
fact,NN,O
that,IN,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
's,POS,O
constitution,NN,O
highly,RB,O
centralizes,VBZ,O
power,NN,O
in,IN,O
Montgomery,NNP,I-LOC
and,CC,O
leaves,VBZ,O
practically,RB,O
no,DT,O
power,NN,O
in,IN,O
local,JJ,O
hands,NNS,O
.,.,O
Any,DT,O
policy,NN,O
changes,NNS,O
proposed,VBN,O
around,IN,O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
must,MD,O
be,VB,O
approved,VBN,O
by,IN,O
the,DT,O
entire,JJ,O
Alabama,NNP,I-ORG
legislature,NN,I-ORG
and,CC,O
",",",",O
frequently,RB,O
",",",",O
by,IN,O
state,NN,O
referendum,NN,O
.,.,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
is,VBZ,O
divided,VBN,O
into,IN,O
three,CD,O
equal,JJ,O
branches,NNS,O
:,IN,O
The,DT,O
legislative,JJ,O
branch,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
the,DT,O
Alabama,NNP,I-ORG
Legislature,NNP,I-ORG
",",",",O
a,DT,O
bicameral,JJ,O
assembly,NN,O
composed,VBN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
House,NNP,I-LOC
of,IN,I-LOC
Representatives,NNPS,I-LOC
",",",",O
with,IN,O
105,CD,O
members,NNS,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
the,DT,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
Senate,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
with,IN,O
35,CD,O
members,NNS,O
.,.,O
It,PRP,O
is,VBZ,O
headed,VBN,O
by,IN,O
the,DT,O
Governor,NNP,O
of,IN,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
The,DT,O
highest,JJS,O
court,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
the,DT,O
Supreme,NNP,I-LOC
Court,NNP,I-LOC
of,IN,I-LOC
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
has,VBZ,O
67,CD,O
counties,NNS,O
.,.,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
is,VBZ,O
an,DT,O
alcoholic,JJ,O
beverage,NN,O
control,NN,O
state,NN,O
;,;,O
the,DT,O
government,NN,O
holds,VBZ,O
a,DT,O
monopoly,NN,O
on,IN,O
the,DT,O
sale,NN,O
of,IN,O
alcohol,NN,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
current,JJ,O
governor,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
Republican,JJ,I-MISC
Bob,NNP,I-PER
Riley,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
The,DT,O
lieutenant,NN,O
governor,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
Jim,NNP,I-PER
Folsom,NNP,I-PER
Jr,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
The,DT,O
Chief,NNP,O
Justice,NNP,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
Supreme,NNP,I-LOC
Court,NNP,I-LOC
is,VBZ,O
Democrat,NNP,I-ORG
Sue,NNP,I-PER
Bell,NNP,I-PER
Cobb,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
The,DT,O
voters,NNS,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
revolted,VBD,O
at,IN,O
what,WP,O
they,PRP,O
perceived,VBD,O
as,IN,O
disenfranchisement,NN,O
of,IN,O
their,PRP$,O
right,NN,O
to,TO,O
vote,VB,O
and,CC,O
elected,VBD,O
the,DT,O
Republican,JJ,I-MISC
challenger,NN,O
Guy,NNP,I-PER
Hunt,NNP,I-PER
as,IN,O
Governor,NNP,O
.,.,O
Republicans,NNPS,I-MISC
hold,VBP,O
an,DT,O
8,CD,O
--,:,O
1,CD,O
majority,NN,O
on,IN,O
the,DT,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
Supreme,NNP,I-LOC
Court,NNP,I-LOC
and,CC,O
have,VB,O
a,DT,O
5,CD,O
--,IN,O
2,CD,O
majority,NN,O
among,IN,O
statewide,JJ,O
elected,JJ,O
executive,NN,O
branch,NN,O
offices,NNS,O
.,.,O
A,DT,O
majority,NN,O
of,IN,O
local,JJ,O
offices,NNS,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
are,VBP,O
still,RB,O
held,VBN,O
by,IN,O
Democrats,NNPS,I-ORG
.,.,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
state,NN,O
politics,NNS,O
gained,VBD,O
nationwide,JJ,O
and,CC,O
international,JJ,O
attention,NN,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
1950s,NNS,O
and,CC,O
1960s,NNS,O
during,IN,O
the,DT,O
American,NNP,I-ORG
Civil,NNP,I-ORG
Rights,NNP,I-ORG
Movement,NNP,I-ORG
",",",",O
when,WRB,O
majority,NN,O
whites,NNS,O
bureaucratically,RB,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
at,IN,O
times,NNS,O
",",",",O
violently,RB,O
resisted,VBD,O
protests,NNS,O
for,IN,O
electoral,JJ,O
and,CC,O
social,JJ,O
reform,NN,O
.,.,O
George,NNP,I-PER
Wallace,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
's,POS,O
governor,NN,O
",",",",O
remains,VBZ,O
a,DT,O
notorious,JJ,O
and,CC,O
controversial,JJ,O
figure,NN,O
.,.,O
In,IN,O
2004,CD,O
",",",",O
George,NNP,I-PER
W.,NNP,I-PER
Bush,NNP,I-PER
won,VBD,O
Alabama,NNP,I-LOC
's,POS,O
nine,CD,O
electoral,JJ,O
votes,NNS,O
by,IN,O
a,DT,O
margin,NN,O
of,IN,O
25,CD,O
percentage,NN,O
points,NNS,O
with,IN,O
62.5,CD,O
%,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
vote,NN,O
",",",",O
mostly,RB,O
white,JJ,O
voters,NNS,O
.,.,O
Public,JJ,O
primary,JJ,O
and,CC,O
secondary,JJ,O
education,NN,I-ORG
in,IN,I-ORG
Alabama,NNP,I-ORG
is,VBZ,O
under,IN,O
the,DT,O
overview,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
Alabama,NNP,I-ORG
State,NNP,I-ORG
Board,NNP,I-ORG
of,IN,I-ORG
Education,NNP,I-ORG
as,RB,O
well,RB,O
as,IN,O
local,JJ,O
oversight,NN,O
by,IN,O
67,CD,O
county,NN,O
school,NN,O
boards,NNS,O
and,CC,O
60,CD,O
city,NN,O
boards,NNS,O
of,IN,O
education,NN,O
.,.,O
While,IN,O
Ala.,NNP,I-LOC
's,POS,O
public,JJ,O
education,NN,O
system,NN,O
has,VBZ,O
improved,VBN,O
",",",",O
it,PRP,O
lags,VBZ,O
behind,IN,O
in,IN,O
achievement,NN,O
compared,VBN,O
to,TO,O
other,JJ,O
states,NNS,O
.,.,O
In,IN,O
the,DT,O
state,NN,O
are,VBP,O
two,CD,O
medical,JJ,O
schools,NNS,O
(,LRB,O
University,NNP,I-ORG
of,IN,I-ORG
Alabama,NNP,I-ORG
at,IN,I-ORG
Birmingham,NNP,I-ORG
and,CC,O
University,NNP,I-ORG
of,IN,I-ORG
South,NNP,I-ORG
Alabama,NNP,I-ORG
),RRB,O
",",",",O
two,CD,O
veterinary,JJ,O
colleges,NNS,O
(,LRB,O
Auburn,NNP,I-ORG
University,NNP,I-ORG
and,CC,O
Tuskegee,NNP,I-ORG
University,NNP,I-ORG
),RRB,O
",",",",O
a,DT,O
dental,JJ,O
school,NN,O
(,LRB,O
University,NNP,I-ORG
of,IN,I-ORG
Alabama,NNP,I-ORG
at,IN,I-ORG
Birmingham,NNP,I-ORG
),RRB,O
",",",",O
an,DT,O
optometry,JJ,O
college,NN,O
(,LRB,O
University,NNP,I-ORG
of,IN,I-ORG
Alabama,NNP,I-ORG
at,IN,I-ORG
Birmingham,NNP,I-ORG
),RRB,O
",",",",O
two,CD,O
pharmacy,JJ,O
schools,NNS,O
(,LRB,O
Auburn,NNP,I-ORG
University,NNP,I-ORG
and,CC,O
Samford,NNP,I-ORG
University,NNP,I-ORG
),RRB,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
five,CD,O
law,NN,O
schools,NNS,O
(,LRB,O
University,NNP,I-ORG
of,IN,I-ORG
Alabama,NNP,I-ORG
School,NNP,I-ORG
of,IN,I-ORG
Law,NNP,I-ORG
",",",",O
Birmingham,NNP,I-ORG
School,NNP,I-ORG
of,IN,I-ORG
Law,NNP,I-ORG
",",",",O
Cumberland,NNP,I-ORG
School,NNP,I-ORG
of,IN,I-ORG
Law,NNP,I-ORG
",",",",O
Miles,NNP,I-ORG
Law,NNP,I-ORG
School,NNP,I-ORG
",",",",O
and,CC,O
the,DT,O
Thomas,NNP,I-ORG
Goode,NNP,I-ORG
Jones,NNP,I-ORG
School,NNP,I-ORG
of,IN,I-ORG
Law,NNP,I-ORG
),RRB,O
.,.,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
also,RB,O
has,VBZ,O
the,DT,O
attributes,NNS,O
of,IN,O
being,VBG,O
the,DT,O
most,JJS,O
handsome,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
heroes,NNS,O
assembled,VBN,O
against,IN,O
Troy,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
Later,RB,O
legends,NNS,O
state,NN,O
that,IN,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
was,VBD,O
invulnerable,JJ,O
in,IN,O
all,DT,O
of,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
body,NN,O
except,IN,O
for,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
heel,NN,O
.,.,O
Zeus,NNP,I-PER
and,CC,O
Poseidon,NNP,I-PER
had,VBD,O
been,VBN,O
rivals,NNS,O
for,IN,O
the,DT,O
hand,NN,O
of,IN,O
Thetis,NNP,I-PER
until,IN,O
Prometheus,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
the,DT,O
fire-bringer,NN,O
",",",",O
warned,VBD,O
Zeus,NNP,I-PER
of,IN,O
a,DT,O
prophecy,NN,O
that,IN,O
Thetis,NNP,I-PER
would,MD,O
bear,VB,O
a,DT,O
son,NN,O
greater,JJR,O
than,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
father,NN,O
.,.,O
For,IN,O
this,DT,O
reason,NN,O
",",",",O
the,DT,O
two,CD,O
gods,NNS,O
withdrew,VBD,O
their,PRP$,O
pursuit,NN,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
had,VBD,O
her,PRP$,O
wed,VBN,O
Peleus,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
As,IN,O
with,IN,O
most,JJS,O
mythology,NN,O
there,EX,O
is,VBZ,O
a,DT,O
tale,NN,O
which,WDT,O
offers,VBZ,O
an,DT,O
alternative,JJ,O
version,NN,O
of,IN,O
these,DT,O
events,NNS,O
:,IN,O
in,IN,O
Argonautica,NNP,I-MISC
(,LRB,O
iv.760,CD,O
),RRB,O
Hera,NNP,I-PER
alludes,VBZ,O
to,TO,O
Thetis,NNP,I-PER
's,POS,O
chaste,NN,O
resistance,NN,O
to,TO,O
the,DT,O
advances,NNS,O
of,IN,O
Zeus,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
that,IN,O
Thetis,NNP,I-PER
was,VBD,O
so,SO,O
loyal,JJ,O
to,TO,O
Hera,NNP,I-PER
's,POS,O
marriage,NN,O
bond,NN,O
that,IN,O
she,PRP,O
coolly,RB,O
rejected,VBD,O
him,PRP,O
.,.,O
In,IN,O
another,DT,O
version,NN,O
of,IN,O
this,DT,O
story,NN,O
",",",",O
Thetis,NNP,I-PER
anointed,VBD,O
the,DT,O
boy,NN,O
in,IN,O
ambrosia,NN,O
and,CC,O
put,VBD,O
him,PRP,O
on,IN,O
top,NN,O
of,IN,O
a,DT,O
fire,NN,O
to,TO,O
burn,VB,O
away,RP,O
the,DT,O
mortal,JJ,O
parts,NNS,O
of,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
body,NN,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
first,JJ,O
two,CD,O
lines,NNS,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
Iliad,NNP,I-MISC
read,NN,O
:,:,O
The,DT,O
humanization,NN,O
of,IN,O
Achilles,NNS,I-PER
by,IN,O
the,DT,O
events,NNS,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
war,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
an,DT,O
important,JJ,O
theme,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
narrative,NN,O
.,.,O
In,IN,O
the,DT,O
resulting,JJ,O
battle,NN,O
",",",",O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
gave,VBD,O
Telephus,NNP,I-PER
a,DT,O
wound,NN,O
that,WDT,O
would,MD,O
not,RB,O
heal,VB,O
;,;,O
Telephus,NNP,I-PER
consulted,VBD,O
an,DT,O
oracle,NN,O
",",",",O
who,WP,O
stated,VBD,O
that,IN,O
"""",LQU,O
he,PRP,O
that,WDT,O
wounded,VBD,O
shall,MD,O
heal,VB,O
"""",RQU,O
.,.,O
Odysseus,NNP,I-PER
reasoned,VBD,O
that,IN,O
the,DT,O
spear,NN,O
had,VBD,O
inflicted,VBN,O
the,DT,O
wound,NN,O
;,;,O
therefore,RB,O
",",",",O
the,DT,O
spear,NN,O
must,MD,O
be,VB,O
able,JJ,O
to,TO,O
heal,VB,O
it,PRP,O
.,.,O
Pieces,NNS,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
spear,NN,O
were,VBD,O
scraped,VBN,O
off,RP,O
onto,IN,O
the,DT,O
wound,NN,O
and,CC,O
Telephus,NN,I-PER
was,VBD,O
healed,VBN,O
.,.,O
Despite,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
youth,NN,O
",",",",O
he,PRP,O
was,VBD,O
one,CD,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
main,JJ,O
Trojan,NN,I-MISC
war,NN,I-MISC
leaders,NNS,O
.,.,O
Later,RB,O
versions,NNS,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
story,NN,O
suggested,VBD,O
Troilus,NNP,I-PER
was,VBD,O
accidentally,RB,O
killed,VBN,O
by,IN,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
in,IN,O
an,DT,O
over-ardent,JJ,O
lovers,NNS,O
',POS,O
embrace,NN,O
.,.,O
Ancient,JJ,O
writers,NNS,O
treated,VBD,O
Troilus,NN,I-PER
as,IN,O
the,DT,O
epitome,NN,O
of,IN,O
a,DT,O
dead,JJ,O
child,NN,O
mourned,VBN,O
by,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
parents,NNS,O
.,.,O
Agamemnon,NNP,I-PER
had,VBD,O
taken,VBN,O
a,DT,O
woman,NN,O
named,VBN,O
Chryseis,NNP,I-PER
as,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
slave,NN,O
.,.,O
Her,PRP$,O
father,NN,O
Chryses,NNS,I-PER
",",",",O
a,DT,O
priest,NN,O
of,IN,O
Apollo,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
begged,VBD,O
Agamemnon,NNP,I-PER
to,TO,O
return,VB,O
her,PRP$,O
to,TO,O
him,PRP,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
prophet,NN,O
Calchas,NNP,I-PER
correctly,RB,O
determined,VBD,O
the,DT,O
source,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
troubles,NNS,O
but,CC,O
would,MD,O
not,RB,O
speak,VB,O
unless,IN,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
vowed,VBD,O
to,TO,O
protect,VB,O
him,PRP,O
.,.,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
did,VBD,O
so,RB,O
and,CC,O
Calchas,NNP,I-PER
declared,VBD,O
Chryseis,NNP,I-PER
must,MD,O
be,VB,O
returned,VBN,O
to,TO,O
her,PRP$,O
father,NN,O
.,.,O
Agamemnon,NNP,I-PER
agreed,VBD,O
and,CC,O
sent,VBD,O
Odysseus,NNP,I-PER
and,CC,O
two,CD,O
other,JJ,O
chieftains,NNS,O
",",",",O
Ajax,NNP,I-PER
and,CC,O
Phoenix,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
to,TO,O
Achilles,NNS,I-PER
with,IN,O
the,DT,O
offer,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
return,NN,O
of,IN,O
Briseis,NNP,I-PER
and,CC,O
other,JJ,O
gifts,NNS,O
.,.,O
After,IN,O
receiving,VBG,O
the,DT,O
news,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
death,NN,O
of,IN,O
Patroclus,NN,I-PER
from,IN,O
Antilochus,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
the,DT,O
son,NN,O
of,IN,O
Nestor,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
grieved,VBD,O
over,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
cousin,NN,O
's,POS,O
death,NN,O
and,CC,O
held,VBD,O
many,JJ,O
funeral,JJ,O
games,NNS,O
in,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
honor,NN,O
.,.,O
His,PRP$,O
mother,NN,O
Thetis,NNS,I-PER
came,VBD,O
to,TO,O
comfort,NN,O
the,DT,O
distraught,NN,O
Achilles,VBZ,I-PER
.,.,O
She,PRP,O
persuaded,VBD,O
Hephaestus,NNP,I-PER
to,TO,O
make,VB,O
new,JJ,O
armor,NN,O
for,IN,O
him,PRP,O
",",",",O
in,IN,O
place,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
armor,NN,O
that,IN,O
Patroclus,NNP,I-PER
had,VBD,O
been,VBN,O
wearing,VBG,O
which,WDT,O
was,VBD,O
taken,VBN,O
by,IN,O
Hector,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
even,RB,O
engaged,VBD,O
in,IN,O
battle,NN,O
with,IN,O
the,DT,O
river,NN,O
god,NN,O
Scamander,NNP,I-PER
who,WP,O
became,VBD,O
angry,JJ,O
that,IN,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
was,VBD,O
choking,VBG,O
his,PRP$,O
waters,NNS,O
with,IN,O
all,PDT,O
the,DT,O
men,NNS,O
he,PRP,O
killed,VBD,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
god,NN,O
tried,VBD,O
to,TO,O
drown,VB,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
but,CC,O
was,VBD,O
stopped,VBN,O
by,IN,O
Hera,NNP,I-PER
and,CC,O
Hephaestus,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
Finally,RB,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
found,VBD,O
his,PRP$,O
prey,NN,O
.,.,O
After,IN,O
Hector,NNP,I-PER
realized,VBD,O
the,DT,O
trick,NN,O
",",",",O
he,PRP,O
knew,VBD,O
the,DT,O
battle,NN,O
was,VBD,O
inevitable,JJ,O
.,.,O
Wanting,VBG,O
to,TO,O
go,VB,O
down,RP,O
fighting,NN,O
",",",",O
he,PRP,O
charged,VBD,O
at,IN,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
with,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
only,JJ,O
weapon,NN,O
",",",",O
his,PRP$,O
sword,NN,O
",",",",O
but,CC,O
missed,VBD,O
.,.,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
told,VBD,O
Hector,NNP,I-PER
it,PRP,O
was,VBD,O
hopeless,JJ,O
to,TO,O
expect,VB,O
that,DT,O
of,IN,O
him,PRP,O
",",",",O
declaring,VBG,O
that,IN,O
"""",LQU,O
my,PRP$,O
rage,NN,O
",",",",O
my,PRP$,O
fury,NN,O
would,MD,O
drive,VB,O
me,PRP,O
now,RB,O
to,TO,O
hack,VB,O
your,PRP$,O
flesh,NN,O
away,RB,O
and,CC,O
eat,VB,O
you,PRP,O
raw,JJ,O
--,:,O
such,JJ,O
agonies,NNS,O
you,PRP,O
have,VBP,O
caused,VBN,O
me,PRP,O
"""",RQU,O
.,.,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
after,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
temporary,JJ,O
truce,NN,O
with,IN,O
Priam,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
fought,VBD,O
and,CC,O
killed,VBD,O
the,DT,O
Amazonian,JJ,I-MISC
warrior,NN,O
queen,NN,O
Penthesilea,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
but,CC,O
later,RB,O
grieved,VBN,O
over,IN,O
her,PRP$,O
death,NN,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
Aethiopis,NNP,I-MISC
is,VBZ,O
now,RB,O
lost,VBN,O
",",",",O
except,IN,O
for,IN,O
scattered,JJ,O
fragments,NNS,O
quoted,VBN,O
by,IN,O
later,JJ,O
authors,NNS,O
.,.,O
As,IN,O
predicted,VBN,O
by,IN,O
Hector,NNP,I-PER
with,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
dying,JJ,O
breath,NN,O
",",",",O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
was,VBD,O
thereafter,RB,O
killed,VBN,O
by,IN,O
Paris,NNP,I-PER
with,IN,O
an,DT,O
arrow,NN,O
(,LRB,O
to,TO,O
the,DT,O
heel,NN,O
according,VBG,O
to,TO,O
Statius,NNP,I-PER
),RRB,O
.,.,O
In,IN,O
some,DT,O
versions,NNS,O
",",",",O
the,DT,O
god,NN,O
Apollo,NNP,I-PER
guided,VBD,O
Paris,NNP,I-PER
',POS,O
arrow,NN,O
.,.,O
Both,DT,O
versions,NNS,O
conspicuously,RB,O
deny,VBP,O
the,DT,O
killer,NN,O
any,DT,O
sort,NN,O
of,IN,O
valor,NN,O
owing,VBG,O
to,TO,O
the,DT,O
common,JJ,O
conception,NN,O
that,IN,O
Paris,NNP,I-PER
was,VBD,O
a,DT,O
coward,NN,O
and,CC,O
not,RB,O
the,DT,O
man,NN,O
his,PRP$,O
brother,NN,O
Hector,NNP,I-PER
was,VBD,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
remained,VBD,O
undefeated,JJ,O
on,IN,O
the,DT,O
battlefield,NN,O
.,.,O
His,PRP$,O
bones,NNS,O
were,VBD,O
mingled,VBN,O
with,IN,O
those,DT,O
of,IN,O
Patroclus,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
and,CC,O
funeral,JJ,O
games,NNS,O
were,VBD,O
held,VBN,O
.,.,O
Priam,NNP,I-PER
is,VBZ,O
willing,JJ,O
because,IN,O
it,PRP,O
would,MD,O
mean,VB,O
the,DT,O
end,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
war,NN,O
and,CC,O
an,DT,O
alliance,NN,O
with,IN,O
the,DT,O
world,NN,O
's,POS,O
greatest,JJS,O
warrior,NN,O
.,.,O
But,CC,O
while,IN,O
Priam,NNP,I-PER
is,VBZ,O
overseeing,VBG,O
the,DT,O
private,JJ,O
marriage,NN,O
of,IN,O
Polyxena,NNP,I-PER
and,CC,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
Paris,NNP,I-PER
who,WP,O
would,MD,O
have,VB,O
to,TO,O
give,VB,O
up,RP,O
Helen,NNP,I-PER
if,IN,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
married,VBD,O
his,PRP$,O
sister,NN,O
hides,NNS,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
bushes,NNS,O
and,CC,O
shoots,NNS,O
Achilles,NNS,I-PER
with,IN,O
a,DT,O
divine,JJ,O
arrow,NN,O
killing,VBG,O
him,PRP,O
.,.,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
was,VBD,O
cremated,VBN,O
and,CC,O
his,PRP$,O
ashes,NNS,O
buried,VBN,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
same,JJ,O
urn,NN,O
as,IN,O
those,DT,O
of,IN,O
Patroclus,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
Paris,NNP,I-PER
was,VBD,O
later,RB,O
killed,VBN,O
by,IN,O
Philoctetes,NNP,I-PER
using,VBG,O
the,DT,O
enormous,JJ,O
bow,NN,O
of,IN,O
Heracles,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
Furious,JJ,O
",",",",O
Ajax,NNP,I-PER
cursed,VBD,O
Odysseus,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
which,WDT,O
earned,VBD,O
the,DT,O
ire,NN,O
of,IN,O
Athena,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
Athena,NNP,I-PER
temporarily,RB,O
made,VBD,O
Ajax,NNP,I-PER
so,SO,O
mad,JJ,O
with,IN,O
grief,NN,O
and,CC,O
anguish,NN,O
that,IN,O
he,PRP,O
began,VBD,O
killing,VBG,O
sheep,NN,O
",",",",O
thinking,VBG,O
they,PRP,O
are,VBP,O
his,PRP$,O
comrades,NNS,O
.,.,O
Odysseus,NNP,I-PER
eventually,RB,O
gave,VBD,O
the,DT,O
armor,NN,O
to,TO,O
Neoptolemus,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
the,DT,O
son,NN,O
of,IN,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
The,DT,O
city,NN,O
was,VBD,O
visited,VBN,O
in,IN,O
333,CD,O
BC,NNP,O
by,IN,O
Alexander,NNP,I-PER
the,DT,I-PER
Great,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
who,WP,O
envisioned,VBD,O
himself,PRP,O
as,IN,O
the,DT,O
new,JJ,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
and,CC,O
carried,VBD,O
the,DT,O
Iliad,NN,I-MISC
with,IN,O
him,PRP,O
",",",",O
but,CC,O
his,PRP$,O
court,NN,O
biographers,NNS,O
do,VBP,O
not,RB,O
mention,VB,O
the,DT,O
spear,NN,O
",",",",O
which,WDT,O
he,PRP,O
would,MD,O
indeed,RB,O
have,VB,O
touched,VBN,O
with,IN,O
excitement,NN,O
.,.,O
In,IN,O
the,DT,O
Iliad,NNP,I-MISC
",",",",O
they,PRP,O
appeared,VBD,O
to,TO,O
be,VB,O
generally,RB,O
portrayed,VBN,O
as,IN,O
a,DT,O
model,NN,O
of,IN,O
deep,JJ,O
and,CC,O
loyal,JJ,O
friendship,NN,O
.,.,O
Pausanias,NNP,I-PER
has,VBZ,O
been,VBN,O
told,VBN,O
that,IN,O
the,DT,O
island,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
"""",LQU,O
covered,VBN,O
with,IN,O
forests,NNS,O
and,CC,O
full,JJ,O
of,IN,O
animals,NNS,O
",",",",O
some,DT,O
wild,JJ,O
",",",",O
some,DT,O
tame,NN,O
.,.,O
This,DT,O
island,NN,O
is,VBZ,O
not,RB,O
inhabited,VBN,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
goats,NNS,O
graze,VBP,O
on,IN,O
it,PRP,O
",",",",O
not,RB,O
many,JJ,O
",",",",O
which,WDT,O
the,DT,O
people,NNS,O
who,WP,O
happen,VBP,O
to,TO,O
arrive,VB,O
here,RB,O
with,IN,O
their,PRP$,O
ships,NNS,O
",",",",O
sacrifice,NN,O
to,TO,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
In,IN,O
this,DT,O
temple,NN,O
are,VBP,O
also,RB,O
deposited,VBN,O
a,DT,O
great,JJ,O
many,JJ,O
holy,JJ,O
gifts,NNS,O
",",",",O
craters,NNS,O
",",",",O
rings,NNS,O
and,CC,O
precious,JJ,O
stones,NNS,O
",",",",O
offered,VBN,O
to,TO,O
Achilles,NNS,I-PER
in,IN,O
gratitude,NN,O
.,.,O
Some,DT,O
of,IN,O
these,DT,O
are,VBP,O
worded,VBN,O
in,IN,O
Patroclus,NNP,I-PER
',POS,O
honor,NN,O
",",",",O
because,IN,O
those,DT,O
who,WP,O
wish,VBP,O
to,TO,O
be,VB,O
favored,VBN,O
by,IN,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
honor,NN,O
Patroclus,NN,I-PER
at,IN,O
the,DT,O
same,JJ,O
time,NN,O
.,.,O
To,TO,O
some,DT,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
people,NNS,O
who,WP,O
come,VBP,O
to,TO,O
this,DT,O
island,NN,O
",",",",O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
appears,VBZ,O
in,IN,O
dreams,NNS,O
",",",",O
to,TO,O
others,NNS,O
he,PRP,O
would,MD,O
appear,VB,O
even,RB,O
during,IN,O
their,PRP$,O
navigation,NN,O
",",",",O
if,IN,O
they,PRP,O
were,VBD,O
not,RB,O
too,RB,O
far,RB,O
away,RB,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
would,MD,O
instruct,VB,O
them,PRP,O
as,IN,O
to,TO,O
which,WDT,O
part,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
island,NN,O
they,PRP,O
would,MD,O
better,RB,O
anchor,VB,O
their,PRP$,O
ships,NNS,O
"""",RQU,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
heroic,JJ,O
cult,NN,O
of,IN,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
on,IN,O
Leuce,NNP,I-LOC
island,NN,O
was,VBD,O
widespread,JJ,O
in,IN,O
antiquity,NN,O
",",",",O
not,RB,O
only,RB,O
along,IN,O
the,DT,O
sea,NN,O
lanes,NNS,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
Pontic,NNP,I-LOC
Sea,NNP,I-LOC
but,CC,O
also,RB,O
in,IN,O
maritime,NN,O
cities,NNS,O
whose,WP$,O
economic,JJ,O
interests,NNS,O
were,VBD,O
tightly,RB,O
connected,VBN,O
to,TO,O
the,DT,O
riches,NNS,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
Black,NNP,I-LOC
Sea,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
Leuce,NNP,I-LOC
had,VBD,O
also,RB,O
a,DT,O
reputation,NN,O
as,IN,O
a,DT,O
place,NN,O
of,IN,O
healing,NN,O
.,.,O
Ammianus,NNP,I-PER
Marcellinus,NNP,I-PER
attributes,VBZ,O
the,DT,O
healing,NN,O
to,TO,O
waters,NNS,O
(,LRB,O
aquae,NN,O
),RRB,O
on,IN,O
the,DT,O
island,NN,O
.,.,O
Some,DT,O
post-Homeric,JJ,I-PER
sources,NNS,O
claim,VBP,O
that,IN,O
in,IN,O
order,NN,O
to,TO,O
keep,VB,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
safe,JJ,O
from,IN,O
the,DT,O
war,NN,O
",",",",O
Thetis,NNP,I-PER
(,LRB,O
or,CC,O
",",",",O
in,IN,O
some,DT,O
versions,NNS,O
",",",",O
Peleus,NNP,I-PER
),RRB,O
hides,VBZ,O
the,DT,O
young,JJ,O
man,NN,O
at,IN,O
the,DT,O
court,NN,O
of,IN,O
Lycomedes,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
king,NN,O
of,IN,O
Skyros,NNS,I-LOC
.,.,O
With,IN,O
Lycomedes,NNP,I-PER
',POS,O
daughter,NN,O
Deidamia,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
whom,WP,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
account,NN,O
of,IN,O
Statius,NNP,I-PER
he,PRP,O
rapes,VBZ,O
",",",",O
Achilles,VBZ,I-PER
there,EX,O
fathers,VBZ,O
a,DT,O
son,NN,O
",",",",O
Neoptolemus,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
Odysseus,NNP,I-PER
goes,VBZ,O
to,TO,O
Skyros,NNS,I-LOC
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
guise,NN,O
of,IN,O
a,DT,O
peddler,NN,O
selling,VBG,O
women,NNS,O
's,POS,O
clothes,NNS,O
and,CC,O
jewelry,NN,O
and,CC,O
places,VBZ,O
a,DT,O
shield,NN,O
and,CC,O
spear,NN,O
among,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
goods,NNS,O
.,.,O
In,IN,O
another,DT,O
version,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
story,NN,O
",",",",O
Odysseus,NNP,I-PER
arranges,VBZ,O
for,IN,O
a,DT,O
trumpet,NN,O
alarm,NN,O
to,TO,O
be,VB,O
sounded,VBN,O
while,IN,O
he,PRP,O
was,VBD,O
with,IN,O
Lycomedes,NNP,I-PER
',POS,O
women,NNS,O
;,;,O
while,IN,O
the,DT,O
women,NNS,O
flee,VBP,O
in,IN,O
panic,NN,O
",",",",O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
prepares,VBZ,O
to,TO,O
defend,VB,O
the,DT,O
court,NN,O
",",",",O
thus,RB,O
giving,VBG,O
his,PRP$,O
identity,NN,O
away,RB,O
.,.,O
In,IN,O
book,NN,O
11,CD,O
of,IN,O
Homer,NNP,I-PER
's,POS,O
Odyssey,NNP,I-MISC
",",",",O
Odysseus,NNP,I-PER
sails,VBZ,O
to,TO,O
the,DT,O
underworld,NN,O
and,CC,O
converses,NNS,O
with,IN,O
the,DT,O
shades,NNS,O
.,.,O
But,CC,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
then,RB,O
asks,VBZ,O
Odysseus,NN,I-PER
of,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
son,NN,O
's,POS,O
exploits,NNS,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
Trojan,NNP,I-MISC
war,NN,I-MISC
",",",",O
and,CC,O
when,WRB,O
Odysseus,NNP,I-PER
tells,VBZ,O
of,IN,O
Neoptolemus,NNP,I-PER
',POS,O
heroic,JJ,O
actions,NNS,O
",",",",O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
is,VBZ,O
filled,VBN,O
with,IN,O
satisfaction,NN,O
.,.,O
This,DT,O
leaves,VBZ,O
the,DT,O
reader,NN,O
with,IN,O
an,DT,O
ambiguous,JJ,O
understanding,NN,O
of,IN,O
how,WRB,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
felt,VBD,O
about,IN,O
the,DT,O
heroic,JJ,O
life,NN,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
kings,NNS,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
Epirus,NNP,I-MISC
claimed,VBD,O
to,TO,O
be,VB,O
descended,VBN,O
from,IN,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
through,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
son,NN,O
",",",",O
Neoptolemus,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
In,IN,O
some,DT,O
versions,NNS,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
myth,NN,O
",",",",O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
has,VBZ,O
a,DT,O
relationship,NN,O
with,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
captive,JJ,O
Briseis,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
The,DT,O
tragedies,NNS,O
relate,VBP,O
the,DT,O
deeds,NNS,O
of,IN,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
during,IN,O
the,DT,O
Trojan,NNP,I-MISC
War,NNP,I-MISC
",",",",O
including,VBG,O
his,PRP$,O
defeat,NN,O
of,IN,O
Hector,NNP,I-PER
and,CC,O
eventual,JJ,O
death,NN,O
when,WRB,O
an,DT,O
arrow,NN,O
shot,NN,O
by,IN,O
Paris,NNP,I-PER
and,CC,O
guided,VBN,O
by,IN,O
Apollo,NNP,I-PER
punctures,VBZ,O
his,PRP$,O
heel,NN,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
role,NN,O
of,IN,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
has,VBZ,O
been,VBN,O
played,VBN,O
by,IN,O
:,:,O
Achilles,NNP,I-PER
has,VBZ,O
frequently,RB,O
been,VBN,O
mentioned,VBN,O
in,IN,O
music,NN,O
.,.,O
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
had,VBD,O
closely,RB,O
supervised,VBN,O
the,DT,O
victorious,JJ,O
war,NN,O
effort,NN,O
",",",",O
especially,RB,O
the,DT,O
selection,NN,O
of,IN,O
top,JJ,O
generals,NNS,O
",",",",O
including,VBG,O
Ulysses,NNP,I-PER
S.,NNP,I-PER
Grant,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
successfully,RB,O
defused,VBD,O
the,DT,O
Trent,NNP,I-MISC
affair,NN,I-MISC
",",",",O
a,DT,O
war,NN,O
scare,NN,O
with,IN,O
Britain,NNP,I-LOC
late,RB,O
in,IN,O
1861,CD,O
.,.,O
Copperheads,NNS,I-ORG
and,CC,O
other,JJ,O
opponents,NNS,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
war,NN,O
criticized,VBD,O
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
for,IN,O
refusing,VBG,O
to,TO,O
compromise,VB,O
on,IN,O
the,DT,O
slavery,NN,O
issue,NN,O
.,.,O
Even,RB,O
with,IN,O
these,DT,O
opponents,NNS,O
",",",",O
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
successfully,RB,O
rallied,VBD,O
public,JJ,O
opinion,NN,O
through,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
rhetoric,NN,O
and,CC,O
speeches,NNS,O
;,;,O
his,PRP$,O
Gettysburg,NNP,I-PER
Address,NNP,I-PER
(,LRB,O
1863,CD,O
),RRB,O
became,VBD,O
an,DT,O
iconic,JJ,O
symbol,NN,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
nation,NN,O
's,POS,O
duty,NN,O
.,.,O
Abraham,NNP,I-PER
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
was,VBD,O
born,VBN,O
on,IN,O
February,NNP,O
12,CD,O
",",",",O
1809,CD,O
",",",",O
to,TO,O
Thomas,NNP,I-PER
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
and,CC,O
Nancy,NNP,I-PER
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
(,LRB,O
née,NN,O
Hanks,NNS,I-PER
),RRB,O
",",",",O
two,CD,O
farmers,NNS,O
",",",",O
in,IN,O
a,DT,O
one-room,JJ,O
log,NN,O
cabin,NN,O
on,IN,O
the,DT,O
348-acre,JJ,O
(,LRB,O
1.4,CD,O
km,NN,O
2,CD,O
),RRB,O
Sinking,VBG,I-LOC
Spring,VBG,I-LOC
Farm,NN,I-LOC
in,IN,O
southeast,JJ,O
Hardin,NNP,I-LOC
County,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
Kentucky,NNP,I-LOC
(,LRB,O
now,RB,O
part,NN,O
of,IN,O
LaRue,NNP,I-LOC
County,NNP,I-LOC
),RRB,O
",",",",O
making,VBG,O
him,PRP,O
the,DT,O
first,JJ,O
president,NN,O
born,VBN,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
west,NN,O
.,.,O
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
was,VBD,O
not,RB,O
given,VBN,O
a,DT,O
middle,JJ,O
name,NN,O
.,.,O
He,PRP,O
owned,VBD,O
several,JJ,O
farms,NNS,O
",",",",O
including,VBG,O
the,DT,O
Sinking,VBG,I-LOC
Spring,NNP,I-LOC
Farm,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
although,IN,O
he,PRP,O
was,VBD,O
not,RB,O
wealthy,JJ,O
.,.,O
Abraham,NNP,I-PER
himself,PRP,O
never,RB,O
joined,VBD,O
their,PRP$,O
church,NN,O
",",",",O
or,CC,O
any,DT,O
other,JJ,O
church,NN,O
.,.,O
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
later,RB,O
noted,VBD,O
that,IN,O
this,DT,O
move,NN,O
was,VBD,O
"""",LQU,O
partly,RB,O
on,IN,O
account,NN,O
of,IN,O
"slavery,",NN,O
"""",RQU,O
and,CC,O
partly,RB,O
because,IN,O
of,IN,O
difficulties,NNS,O
with,IN,O
land,NN,O
deeds,NNS,O
in,IN,O
Kentucky,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
Abraham,NNP,I-PER
's,POS,O
father,NN,O
disapproved,VBD,O
of,IN,O
slavery,NN,O
on,IN,O
religious,JJ,O
grounds,NNS,O
and,CC,O
it,PRP,O
was,VBD,O
hard,JJ,O
to,TO,O
compete,VB,O
economically,RB,O
with,IN,O
farms,NNS,O
operated,VBN,O
by,IN,O
slaves,NNS,O
.,.,O
Unlike,IN,O
land,NN,O
in,IN,O
the,DT,O
Northwest,NNP,I-ORG
Territory,NNP,I-ORG
",",",",O
Kentucky,NNP,I-LOC
never,RB,O
had,VBD,O
a,DT,O
proper,JJ,O
U.S.,NNP,I-LOC
survey,NN,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
farmers,NNS,O
often,RB,O
had,VBD,O
difficulties,NNS,O
proving,VBG,O
title,NN,O
to,TO,O
their,PRP$,O
property,NN,O
.,.,O
When,WRB,O
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
was,VBD,O
nine,CD,O
",",",",O
his,PRP$,O
mother,NN,O
",",",",O
then,RB,O
34,CD,O
years,NNS,O
old,JJ,O
",",",",O
died,VBD,O
of,IN,O
milk,NN,O
sickness,NN,O
.,.,O
Soon,RB,O
afterwards,RB,O
",",",",O
his,PRP$,O
father,NN,O
remarried,VBD,O
",",",",O
to,TO,O
Sarah,NNP,I-PER
Bush,NNP,I-PER
Johnston,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
and,CC,O
his,PRP$,O
stepmother,NN,O
were,VBD,O
close,RB,O
;,;,O
he,PRP,O
called,VBD,O
her,PRP,O
"""",LQU,O
Mother,NNP,O
"""",RQU,O
for,IN,O
the,DT,O
rest,NN,O
of,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
life,NN,O
",",",",O
but,CC,O
he,PRP,O
became,VBD,O
increasingly,RB,O
distant,JJ,O
from,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
father,NN,O
.,.,O
Abraham,NNP,I-PER
felt,VBD,O
his,PRP$,O
father,NN,O
was,VBD,O
not,RB,O
a,DT,O
success,NN,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
did,VBD,O
not,RB,O
want,VB,O
to,TO,O
be,VB,O
like,IN,O
him,PRP,O
.,.,O
In,IN,O
1830,CD,O
",",",",O
fearing,VBG,O
a,DT,O
milk,NN,O
sickness,NN,O
outbreak,NN,O
",",",",O
the,DT,O
family,NN,O
settled,VBD,O
on,IN,O
public,JJ,O
land,NN,O
in,IN,O
Macon,NNP,I-LOC
County,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
Ill.,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
Later,RB,O
that,DT,O
year,NN,O
",",",",O
hired,VBN,O
by,IN,O
New,NNP,I-LOC
Salem,NNP,I-LOC
businessman,NN,O
Denton,NNP,I-PER
Offutt,NNP,I-PER
and,CC,O
accompanied,VBN,O
by,IN,O
friends,NNS,O
",",",",O
he,PRP,O
took,VBD,O
goods,NNS,O
from,IN,O
New,NNP,I-LOC
Salem,NNP,I-LOC
to,TO,O
New,NNP,I-LOC
Orleans,NNP,I-LOC
via,IN,O
flatboat,NN,O
on,IN,O
the,DT,O
Sangamon,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
Illinois,NNP,I-LOC
and,CC,O
Mississippi,NNP,I-LOC
rivers,NNS,O
.,.,O
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
's,POS,O
formal,JJ,O
education,NN,O
consisted,VBD,O
of,IN,O
about,IN,O
18,CD,O
months,NNS,O
of,IN,O
schooling,NN,O
;,;,O
but,CC,O
he,PRP,O
was,VBD,O
an,DT,O
avid,JJ,O
reader,NN,O
and,CC,O
largely,RB,O
self-educated,JJ,O
.,.,O
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
avoided,VBD,O
hunting,NN,O
and,CC,O
fishing,NN,O
because,IN,O
he,PRP,O
did,VBD,O
not,RB,O
like,VB,O
killing,VBG,O
animals,NNS,O
",",",",O
even,RB,O
for,IN,O
food,NN,O
.,.,O
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
's,POS,O
first,JJ,O
love,NN,O
was,VBD,O
Ann,NNP,I-PER
Rutledge,NNP,I-PER
.,.,O
He,PRP,O
met,VBD,O
her,PRP,O
when,WRB,O
he,PRP,O
first,RB,O
moved,VBD,O
to,TO,O
New,NNP,I-LOC
Salem,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
and,CC,O
by,IN,O
1835,CD,O
they,PRP,O
had,VBD,O
reached,VBN,O
a,DT,O
romantic,JJ,O
understanding,NN,O
.,.,O
Rutledge,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
however,RB,O
",",",",O
died,VBD,O
on,IN,O
August,NNP,O
25,CD,O
",",",",O
probably,RB,O
of,IN,O
typhoid,JJ,O
fever,NN,O
.,.,O
In,IN,O
1840,CD,O
",",",",O
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
became,VBD,O
engaged,VBN,O
to,TO,O
Mary,NNP,I-PER
Todd,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
from,IN,O
a,DT,O
wealthy,JJ,O
slaveholding,NN,O
family,NN,O
based,VBN,O
in,IN,O
Lexington,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
Kentucky,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
The,DT,O
Lincolns,NNP,I-PER
soon,RB,O
had,VBD,O
a,DT,O
budding,VBG,O
family,NN,O
",",",",O
with,IN,O
the,DT,O
birth,NN,O
of,IN,O
son,NN,O
Robert,NNP,I-PER
Todd,NNP,I-PER
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
in,IN,O
Springfield,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
Ill.,NNP,I-LOC
on,IN,O
August,NNP,O
1,CD,O
",",",",O
1843,CD,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
second,JJ,O
son,NN,O
Edward,NNP,I-PER
Baker,NNP,I-PER
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
on,IN,O
March,NNP,O
10,CD,O
",",",",O
1846,CD,O
",",",",O
also,RB,O
in,IN,O
Springfield,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
According,VBG,O
to,TO,O
a,DT,O
house,NN,O
girl,NN,O
",",",",O
Abraham,NNP,I-PER
"""",LQU,O
was,VBD,O
remarkably,RB,O
fond,JJ,O
of,IN,O
children,NNS,O
.,.,O
"""",RQU,O
The,DT,O
Lincolns,NNPS,I-PER
did,VBD,O
not,RB,O
believe,VB,O
in,IN,O
strict,JJ,O
rules,NNS,O
and,CC,O
tight,JJ,O
boundaries,NNS,O
when,WRB,O
it,PRP,O
came,VBD,O
to,TO,O
their,PRP$,O
children,NNS,O
.,.,O
Robert,NNP,I-MISC
",",",",O
however,RB,O
",",",",O
would,MD,O
be,VB,O
the,DT,O
only,JJ,O
one,CD,O
of,IN,O
the,DT,O
Lincolns,NNP,I-PER
',POS,O
children,NNS,O
to,TO,O
survive,VB,O
into,IN,O
adulthood,NN,O
.,.,O
Edward,NNP,I-PER
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
died,VBD,O
on,IN,O
February,NNP,O
1,CD,O
",",",",O
1850,CD,O
in,IN,O
Springfield,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
likely,JJ,O
of,IN,O
tuberculosis,NN,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
Lincolns,NNP,I-PER
',POS,O
grief,NN,O
over,IN,O
this,DT,O
loss,NN,O
was,VBD,O
somewhat,RB,O
assuaged,VBN,O
by,IN,O
the,DT,O
birth,NN,O
of,IN,O
William,NNP,I-PER
"""",LQU,I-PER
Willie,NNP,I-PER
"""",RQU,I-PER
Wallace,NNP,I-PER
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
nearly,RB,O
eleven,CD,O
months,NNS,O
later,RB,O
",",",",O
on,IN,O
December,NNP,O
21,CD,O
.,.,O
Robert,NNP,I-PER
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
eventually,RB,O
went,VBD,O
on,IN,O
to,TO,O
attend,VB,O
Phillips,NNP,I-ORG
Exeter,NNP,I-ORG
Academy,NNP,I-ORG
and,CC,O
Harvard,NNP,I-ORG
College,NNP,I-ORG
.,.,O
His,PRP$,O
(,LRB,O
and,CC,O
by,IN,O
extension,NN,O
",",",",O
his,PRP$,O
father,NN,O
's,POS,O
),RRB,O
last,JJ,O
known,VBN,O
lineal,NN,O
descendant,NN,O
",",",",O
Robert,NNP,I-PER
Todd,NNP,I-PER
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
Beckwith,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
died,VBD,O
December,NNP,O
24,CD,O
",",",",O
1985,CD,O
.,.,O
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
began,VBD,O
his,PRP$,O
political,JJ,O
career,NN,O
in,IN,O
March,NNP,O
1832,CD,O
at,IN,O
age,NN,O
23,CD,O
when,WRB,O
he,PRP,O
announced,VBD,O
his,PRP$,O
candidacy,NN,O
for,IN,O
the,DT,O
Illinois,NNP,I-ORG
General,NNP,I-ORG
Assembly,NNP,I-ORG
.,.,O
He,PRP,O
was,VBD,O
esteemed,VBN,O
by,IN,O
the,DT,O
residents,NNS,O
of,IN,O
New,NNP,I-LOC
Salem,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
but,CC,O
he,PRP,O
did,VBD,O
not,RB,O
have,VB,O
an,DT,O
education,NN,O
",",",",O
powerful,JJ,O
friends,NNS,O
",",",",O
or,CC,O
money,NN,O
.,.,O
The,DT,O
centerpiece,NN,O
of,IN,O
his,PRP$,O
platform,NN,O
was,VBD,O
the,DT,O
undertaking,NN,O
of,IN,O
navigational,JJ,O
improvements,NNS,O
on,IN,O
the,DT,O
Sangamon,NNP,I-LOC
River,NNP,I-LOC
.,.,O
Lincoln,NNP,I-PER
returned,VBD,O
from,IN,O
the,DT,O
militia,NN,O
after,IN,O
a,DT,O
few,JJ,O
months,NNS,O
and,CC,O
was,VBD,O
able,JJ,O
to,TO,O
campaign,NN,O
throughout,IN,O
the,DT,O
county,NN,O
before,IN,O
the,DT,O
August,NNP,O
6,CD,O
election,NN,O
.,.,O
Admitted,VBN,O
to,TO,O
the,DT,O
bar,NN,O
in,IN,O
1837,CD,O
",",",",O
he,PRP,O
moved,VBD,O
to,TO,O
Springfield,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
Ill.,NNP,I-LOC
",",",",O
that,IN,O
April,NNP,O
",",",",O
and,CC,O
began,VBD,O
to,TO,O
practice,VB,O
law,NN,O
with,IN,O
John,NNP,I-PER
T.,NNP,I-PER
Stuart,NNP,I-PER
",",",",O
Mary,NNP,I-PER
